<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Relationships | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/categories/relationships/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-22T14:58:42-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twelve-volt reverie]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2010/12/01/twelve-volt-reverie/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-01T18:26:42-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2010/12/01/twelve-volt-reverie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/2072718597/"><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2121/2072718597_7c8ecd7802.jpg" alt="Channing Ave, 11PM." /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m awakened in the morning by a phone call &mdash; It&rsquo;s Mr. Smith, and his car needs a jump. The evening before we had spotted him in the parking lot; he was still seated in his parked car, eyes closed in rapt concentration or heavy sleep, we couldn&rsquo;t tell.</p>

<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s jazz,&rdquo; he explains later. He listens to the jazz giants in his car as is his tradition upon returning home from church. He is aging, his frame is small and hunched, he is becoming forgetful. His car is often parked askew between the lot lines, drifting at odd angles, curious flotsam in an asphalt sea.</p>

<p>Years ago, Miles, John and Dizzy serenade Mr. and Mrs. Smith as they sit together in the driver and passenger seats, holding hands all the way back from church on 98th Ave. There they float and unwind, recounting the events of that evening&rsquo;s ministry. I imagine she smiles at the way his pageboy hat carries at a rakish angle, the way he recites the benediction with the voice of a man much younger than his years. And now I imagine him still sitting in that parking lot, recounting his evening with her, murmuring and chuckling in a half-conscious reverie.</p>

<p>Kind of blue, Mr. Smith drifts to where his beloved still lives, who leans over to playfully adjust his bow tie, takes his wrinkled hands into hers and lets him feel her beating chest where the cancer has not yet gone. There he stays with her, hearing the music well into the morning when the instrument panel will dim, the frost will clamber onto the hood and the chill will irritate his throat and cause him to cough a couple of times. Slow, measured coughs. He turns over in his seat.</p>

<p>I run into the morning chill and see his car is running with the help of a friendly neighbor. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m going to get a new battery,&rdquo; he tells me, fumbling with the jumper cables. With bright, certain eyes he declares, &ldquo;Tomorrow.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Though the word spoken over me today was joy]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2010/07/26/though-the-word-spoken-over-me-today-was-joy/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-26T00:12:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2010/07/26/though-the-word-spoken-over-me-today-was-joy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/4716693560/"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4017/4716693560_ff7eb1619a.jpg" alt="Rancho at the Top" /></a></p>

<p>I am now distraught with sweet, sweet grief in accepting what I do not understand. "Child of weakness watch and pray, find in Me thine all in all."</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[After the fact]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2010/06/28/after-the-fact/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-28T01:13:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2010/06/28/after-the-fact</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>For everything there is a season, and a time for every matter under heaven.</em></p>

<p>Sarah had always made light of the fact that I&rsquo;m like a robot. After all, I work in code all day at my job. And I&rsquo;m stable, familiar, and predictable. And I could always be counted on to &ldquo;do the right thing.&rdquo; And often I have, how shall we say, <em>limited</em> emotional capabilities.</p>

<p>When Sarah and I recently decided to break up after two and a half years together, we both felt strongly that it was for the best. Things had progressed to the point where we didn&rsquo;t feel it was right to move on. She didn&rsquo;t feel understood, I didn&rsquo;t feel accepted. We didn&rsquo;t have the self-awareness to pinpoint a growing uncertainty within. We had been through good times and bad, we were different. But at one point, we had piled up more distance and unresolved conflict than we could afford to handle.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve spent the better part of the month trying to get inside my own head and put the words to what&rsquo;s really going on in me. It&rsquo;s been difficult to know where to start. The first day I was hurt and angry. The second, I was overwhelmed with sadness. The third, I was numb, and so on, in various little permutations. There are days filled with the humdrum of work, the supportive words of a good friend (perhaps you!) and tremendous freedom. And there are days where I&rsquo;m honestly pretty miserable, mourning the loss of shared dreams and a companionship dear to my heart.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read it somewhere that men are often unfairly portrayed as emotionless; they simply don&rsquo;t know how to express what they feel. True; sometimes I feel that having a precise vocabulary and incredible emotional self-awareness will be the tools I need to heal. But if I let this go on too long, I&rsquo;ll never write. Of course, I say this with some embarrassment that what&rsquo;s coming out is completely overdramatic. But I won&rsquo;t apologize for that&hellip; yet.</p>

<p>And in some strange, kinda sick way, it&rsquo;s kind of nice to feel the pain and know that I&rsquo;m not a robot. I&rsquo;m skin and bones, joyously fragile, with little to boast about but the Father who loves me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[To be known, you must know yourself.]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2010/03/26/to-be-known-you-must-know-yourself/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-26T09:45:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2010/03/26/to-be-known-you-must-know-yourself</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am learning that there is a responsibility to being known by another. Sarah and I can&rsquo;t expect to read each other perfectly right off the bat. Nor can we coast off the years we&rsquo;ve been together.</p>

<p>I am only starting to learn about myself. Really. There is work to be done that I&rsquo;ve simply ignored for years. And it&rsquo;s kind of exciting! What motivates me? What makes me mad and why? Why am I the person I am? It&rsquo;s so freaking easy to do the daily routine thing: go to work and come back, fill your life with activities and people and events and commuting that you don&rsquo;t have time to stop and think and just listen.</p>

<p>They say communication is a two-way street, and I&rsquo;m only figuring out that there is much more to plumb from the depths. And it&rsquo;s good for the two of us. If I can explain myself and my feelings and motivations better, then Sarah has more than assumptions to go off on.</p>

<p>And at the same time I realize that this journey of self-realization can be twisted into an exercise in navel-gazing. May I know myself not to make myself more than I really am (a twisted shell of the Original design), but to communicate with ever-more honesty.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How she works]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2010/02/25/how-she-works/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-25T00:09:01-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2010/02/25/how-she-works</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One point of friction between myself and Sarah is that we have a really, really hard time communicating. I mean, it doesn&rsquo;t help that women are elaborate enigmas, and as men we are Astonishingly Dense. Gentlemen, tell me if you&rsquo;ve ever heard the following from your ladies:</p>

<p><em>You just don&rsquo;t get me.</em></p>

<p><em>I wanted you to listen and feel with me.</em></p>

<p><em>Stop giving me solutions and just listen to me.</em></p>

<p><em>Why are you so quiet?</em></p>

<p><em>No, that&rsquo;s not what I meant.</em></p>

<p><em>Are you listening to me?</em></p>

<p><em>I want you to want to.</em></p>

<p><em>I don&rsquo;t have to tell you; you should just know it already.</em></p>

<p><strong>WELL,</strong></p>

<p>Sarah just gave me the Best Valentine&rsquo;s Gift Ever:</p>

<p>[caption id=&ldquo;attachment_1098&rdquo; align=&ldquo;alignnone&rdquo; width=&ldquo;500&rdquo; caption=&ldquo;It&rsquo;s basically like getting the other team&rsquo;s playbook. Everybody wins, so it&rsquo;s even better.&rdquo;]<a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/DSC0378.jpg"><img src="http://www.andrewhao.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/DSC0378-500x332.jpg" alt="" /></a>[/caption]</p>

<p>Sarah made me an instruction manual for Valentine&rsquo;s Day. No, seriously. It&rsquo;s a cute handcrafted book with little snippets of lists of her likes and dislikes, her basic info, and most of all, this mental model and decision diagram of the female brain (well, hers at least).</p>

<p>My logical, rational, Engineer mind rejoices. I love this girl.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
