<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Public | Finding Momentum]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/category/public/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-29T12:47:04-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Hao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First fires]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/11/08/first-fires/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-08T09:56:28-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/11/08/first-fires</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/6325341766/"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6235/6325341766_6102cb11da.jpg" alt="Occupy Oakland" /></a></p>

<p>There was some sort of relief, I decided, in having set foot in the Occupy camp and finding it quiet. Wednesday, Oakland was paraded across the global consciousness as national news media displayed scenes of urban warfare, with ghostly images of terror-stricken faces sent helter-skelter across the airwaves. Zach showed me the frontpage of the BBC website (<em>Occupy Oakland protestors disrupt city</em>) and made a cutting remark about how the protestors were making fools of themselves on global media and how Oakland was going to suffer. The next morning we all got worried emails and well-intentioned text messages from friends and family: <em>hey, you doing okay? </em>to which we&rsquo;d respond with sheepish grace that no, we weren&rsquo;t part of the protests and no, Oakland hadn&rsquo;t burnt to the ground. Yet.</p>

<p>That Saturday we walked the downtown Oakland area and stood among the protestors in Frank Ogawa Plaza and I tried taking it in, inhaling the hot, musty mess, sidling up to the sleeping giant. I&rsquo;m not quite sure what I had expected: chaos, rowdier citizens, widespread aggression and disquiet? Instead we found sleepy-eyed campers, dreadlocked ponytails, and hand-drawn raggedy signs. You could smell the weed from blocks away. Nate confirmed the portable toilets were overflowing and rancid.</p>

<p>Self-conscious, I realized later, is how I feel, not knowing how to identify with this spectacle. My sentiments about the whole thing are less of explosive outrage than subtle helplessness. Here I was, middle-class and Asian-American, walking through the tent city of the dispossessed, and I felt both a repulsion to the sideshow and an isolating sense of guilt knowing that I was a stranger to racial and economic injustice.</p>

<p>We bumped into Bonnie on the way over, a homeless friend of ours who makes appearances often at the church. "You should have been there, they had us <em>cornered</em>&ldquo; she exclaimed with wide eyes, giggling in her two-toned accent. <em>&rdquo;</em>Pohh-leece got us trapped up on both sides. I got some of that gas stuff in me, and it make you tear up real bad."</p>

<p>Bonnie had stayed with the protestors for a couple of days. &ldquo;It was like a <em>war</em>, let me tell you, and the sad thing&rdquo;&mdash;her voice dropped to a whisper&mdash;&ldquo;is nobody can help you.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I wondered what Bonnie must have felt; my mind replayed scenes from a Free Speech Movement documentary I once watched at Cal. Observe: an aerial shot from what must have been a tall building or a helicopter, riot police on either ends of the block, smoke rising from the street in lazy, elegant arcs. Notice: a couple of figures limp for cover, fumbling to cover their eyes. See: grainy film, shot black and white, <em>viva</em> free speech &amp; the cause of justice, <em>fin</em>.</p>

<p>So I was relieved to find Frank Ogawa Plaza rather pleasant. A tent city had risen, built on fresh-laid straw, with hypnotic Native American drumming drifting through camp. Smiling stoners sat cross-legged in a corner beneath a tarp and gazed intently into the distance. A mini-rally proceeded in another, where a megaphone-toting Latina woman was organizing that afternoon&rsquo;s march on Wells Fargo<em>. </em>In other words, it was amusingly like college. We opened our burritos and ate on the steps of the City Hall amphitheater and watched the tent city pulse as it awoke.</p>

<p>The Tuesday night that things got bad, I was running the lake under the assured hum of news helicopters, but I couldn&rsquo;t tell you if things were out of the ordinary. It was strange, I suppose because I had imagined that should my city go down in flames, everybody should know about it and share in the panic and outrage. Women pushed murmuring babies by in fancy strollers. The wind whispered through the grove of trees around the lake&rsquo;s finger-bend. Runners grunted to each other, pushing gravel through the ground. Starlight &amp; Lake Merritt&rsquo;s necklace, swan, geese, &amp; ghetto birds all there to witness war, but somebody had forgotten to remind me.</p>

<p>Saturday, Kylan and Betty and I walked up Telegraph and prayed for Occupy Oakland and I felt rather foolish for not knowing what exactly to pray for. I remembered Silvia&rsquo;s weight of sadness, when she showed up and wound up feeling lost and helpless and hurt for the brokenness of the world she lived in and the chaos unfolding around her and the need for Jesus to show up right there and <em>occupy</em>&hellip;</p>

<p>Proverbs 29 was a comfort, the words breathing and expanding in my thoughts:</p>

<blockquote><p><em>When the righteous increase, the people rejoice but when the wicked rule, people groan</em></p></blockquote>

<p>and,</p>

<blockquote><p><em>The poor and the oppressor meet together, the LORD gives light to them both</em></p></blockquote>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/6325344666/"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6040/6325344666_68f59b38d3.jpg" alt="Occupy Oakland" /></a></p>

<p>Earlier that morning I dreamt we were evacuating our city in long single-file strands. We wound through our neighborhood, and I remember standing in our living room arguing with Justin whether we should load this or that couch into the U-Haul. People shuffled by outside in colorless clothing, feeling here and gone at the same time. Children whispered to each other in shy, hushed tones. The helicopters were there again, whirling lazily, watching overhead. In that moment I knew (though a dream) the question had become not how we would leave, but whether we would stay.</p>

<p>I woke far too early, thirsty, trying to recall how the air felt against my cheeks: <em>thwup thwup thwup thwup thwup.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the other side of autumn]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/10/11/on-the-other-side-of-autumn/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-11T01:20:49-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/10/11/on-the-other-side-of-autumn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/10/11/on-the-other-side-of-autumn/ecef685d4cdd46838de3ad8c6d25515c_7/"><img src="http://www.andrewhao.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/ecef685d4cdd46838de3ad8c6d25515c_7-500x500.jpg" alt="" /></a><a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/10/11/on-the-other-side-of-autumn/e68c24996c324dbdbe77a4f49f20ea60_7/"><img src="http://www.andrewhao.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/e68c24996c324dbdbe77a4f49f20ea60_7-500x500.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>I smelled it coming last week, but it didn&rsquo;t arrive until today. It smelled like autumn, it was warm rain, ticklish; it was musty with diamond dew and faded memories of running through these trees at our old church camp site, redwood trees tickling the clouds and the sweet fragrance of pine cones and the pricks of needles in my shoes. That&rsquo;s the kind of place where the mist envelops your eyes and causes you to blink, over and over and over again. Memories of the bell ringing on the steeple, calling us in for dinner as we would push past adults with understanding smiles to get to turkey and gravy and pumpkin pie, stuffing ourselves and running back out into the wild, pretending we were secret agents.</p>

<p>But there it was again in a different form, carrying us back from LA through the fertile fields of the Central Valley, sunlight streaking over our heads and we drove back and debated whether we were old or not. That previous night at the wedding I asked my table if they&rsquo;d ever really felt <em>old</em>, and that maybe the better question was whether we ever wished we were <em>young</em> again. We all laughed it off, or at least a bit nervously. I wonder if there&rsquo;s a slight terror to the feeling of it overcoming us, afraid that maybe one day we&rsquo;d wake up and feel some gloom of extra gravity and it&rsquo;d hit us: <em>oh crap </em>and we&rsquo;d carry this fear to our twenty-fifth year high school reunions, strung &lsquo;round our necks like medallions. But there rushing past sunkissed fields listening to country crooners I wondered if I&rsquo;d ever really grow old, with the sun on my back and laughter, sweet laughter around me.</p>

<p>I think the warmth of autumn reminds me that all things must change, they must grow and move in season. One day I know I must be old, and I will have known a love that is young and weathered, resilient and yielding and tested True. I will have known the courage of a little boy, spoken to the weighty fears of my young man self, into the maturity that awaits on the other side, the line that we will not know we have crossed until the leaves have long since changed their color.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaning]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/09/12/leaning/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-12T23:45:52-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/09/12/leaning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you lean too hard, you&rsquo;ll go tumbling out of shadows, into the lake. Look, like how the leaves strain against their cuffs in the wind, leaning into the goldenrod breeze. Look at the lovers lean into each other, racing against sundown, lips brushing freckles, freckles brushing blades tickling toes.</p>

<p>There is no time for thinking now, but the mechanical <em>slapslap</em> of feet against pavement. I can sum up Murakami&rsquo;s book: what does he think about when running? Nothing. Justin&rsquo;s been reading more about running lately and letting me read his books. I realize that I enjoy how mechanical it is: I like the forward lean, the rhythmic labor of breathing, driving forward, but not too far forward lest you tumble (where?). I&rsquo;ve been feeling more aggressive with my run form, enjoying the feeling of being <em>fast</em> and the brushing of warm rays on my back. It&rsquo;s going to get me in trouble._
_</p>

<p>I lean into the whoopsiedaisy turn lane and find that will be occupied in three-two-one but thankfully I reel back in and thank my lucky stars. A wandering Kia once leaned into me and gently lay my bike down in the bike lane. I am happy to report I didn&rsquo;t go down with it, but wondered in a few panicked moments if people would do their better thinking laying down.</p>

<p>With much sighing, a flock of photons once barreled into the earth in a lazy arc, leaving tendrils of dirt-dust in its wake. The sun bathed us in a lemonade glow in the evening&mdash;I tried to catch it in the viewfinder, but decided to let the moment stand silent, solemn by my side, the way you would imagine you would feel in one of those movie-moments pregnant with meaning, voiced by a steel guitar. On the way back from Portland I imagined just that, feeling like our car was the only one in the world, leaning into thin slices of daylight. I caught myself singing along to the stereo, and at that moment thought that we should drive to the world&rsquo;s edge, then go some more.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dreams of a city of ash]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/04/15/dreams-of-a-city-of-ash/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-15T11:04:30-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/04/15/dreams-of-a-city-of-ash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/1756742112/"><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2379/1756742112_a54cf5e9a8.jpg" alt="Sensations - Awaken the Dawn" /></a></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s like the evenings I spent in Central Asia years ago, sprawled on a stiff hotel bed and journaling until darkness fell. In my headphones the refrain would play: <em>in your presence, all fear is gone, in your presence&hellip;</em> And it&rsquo;s all I could cling to, because that month-or-so in that land was one of the loneliest I&rsquo;ve had.</p>

<p>That first week, as I was climbing onto the bus, a trio of teenage boys rushed off and shoved me to the side as they exited, so close you could feel the heat radiating off their brows. I thought them rude, but then caught myself and reminded myself that they&rsquo;re just boys. The thought lasted about two seconds; that was the first time I had my wallet stolen.</p>

<p>I still think about the feeling of Sosho and I crammed in the back of the bus, clutching our bags tight (myself, in particular), watching the spires of mosques pass by and watching Muslims pray on the sidewalks during afternoon prayers, their foreheads pressed into the concrete and lips moving in fervent prayer. I remember seeing a diseased boy, his arms both amputated and his face marked with sweat and soot, pleading with his eyes for his throat was parched. Our Muslim friends were generous: they gave alms to the poor, they believed Allah would reward them for their generosity.</p>

<p>The city is one of the most polluted cities in the world; it lies in a dry valley and is reputed as the most landlocked city in the world. Soot and ash from surrounding factories linger over us in a haze. Day by day, thousands of new immigrants arrive by train. The city is exploding; everybody is covered in soot; it is hot; tempers flare, a bus tire explodes and the people begrudgingly walk off the bus and wait for another to come along.</p>

<p>I also remember wandering the parks of that city, and watching the people mill about, their faces blank (as strangers generally are to other strangers), and trying to think about God but constantly being interrupted by the heat and smog, thoughts flitting back and forth from prayer to a red bean popsicle (glory!).</p>

<p>We would hear stories of busloads of South Korean tourists who would come into the city. One of the missionaries told us that they were actually followers of the Way, who would circle the great square in the center of the city and blanket it with prayers. She knew because she would see them walk about, their mouths moving inaudibly and their eyes locked onto the heart of the city and its people. She would see them and her heart would explode and she told us that she would want to shout <em>we&rsquo;re here! we follow the Way too!</em></p>

<p>The weather here is impetuous; one day it&rsquo;ll be 80 degrees and in the evening it&rsquo;ll be below freezing and snowing. It&rsquo;s much like the food, bursting with spices and seasonings and cooled with a dollop of frosty yogurt. The food, oh, I still do dream about it, the <em>lagman</em> and lamb kebabs, the feeling of growing dizzier with the sights and smells of the food stalls at the bazaars.</p>

<p>I wasn&rsquo;t very spiritually-minded on that trip, and I felt that God knew it was okay. I couldn&rsquo;t shake my homesickness on days when I&rsquo;d want to run from the oppressive heat, when the blathering of denizens would take its toll on my patience, and my stomach would rebel at the stream of foreign food I kept trying to feed it with. But still, there was that feeling&mdash;&ndash;</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s like the mornings I&rsquo;d take a jog out onto the deserted streets, watching the sun rise and hearing the burst of an oven igniting, the flapping of pigeon wings, the distant car horn and the slight hum of towering cranes, unofficial city guardians. And though I couldn&rsquo;t shake the homesickness, I knew I was in God&rsquo;s presence. Even today, I look back and know I was with the one they call Allah. I&rsquo;d have these visions of his grace gathering in storm clouds and falling like rain, clearing the air, turning streets into creeks and sprouting trees on their banks.</p>

<p>Soon the ash would fill my lungs and force me, coughing, to turn around and crawl back into bed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Justice and me]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/03/18/justice-and-me/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-18T01:31:15-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/03/18/justice-and-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m wrestling a lot these days with the idea of Justice and what it looks like to be a Christian&mdash;and a human&mdash;in the midst of it.</p>

<p>This week, the <a href="http://interns.regenerationweb.com">interns and I</a> have been at the <a href="http://www.notforsalecampaign.org/news/topic/investigator-academy/">Not for Sale Academy</a> receiving training on human trafficking before we head out to the Philippines in April. I&rsquo;m feeling a lot of heaviness, hearing stories about people held captive under another&rsquo;s power.</p>

<p>A few things I&rsquo;ve been chewing on:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The perversion of masculinity, a fascination (and insecurity) with power, control &amp; ego versus the created Ideal: protective, disciplined, self-sacrificing, Christlike.</p></li>
<li><p>I&rsquo;m nervous about entering darkness; the thought of walking a red-light district scares me. Can I handle it? Also: thoughts on continual prayer as we walk through the shadows. We need to pray to survive.</p></li>
<li><p>I&rsquo;m glad I&rsquo;m going with this group of guys.</p></li>
<li><p>It&rsquo;s okay to feel pain. I&rsquo;m wondering if I even want to be identified with this movement because of the heaviness surrounding it. I&rsquo;m realizing that maybe the pain of the world is what God wants us to feel&mdash;to grieve alongside the broken and the powerless and to be saddened by the injustice in the world.</p></li>
<li><p>On the other side, I&rsquo;m thankful that our God is a God of vengeance and justice. He promises to repay for evil. That is very. comforting. Honestly, I&rsquo;m not sure how I would deal with the brokenness without an Absolute, a Good framework.</p></li>
<li><p>But honestly, I mostly want to turn and go back to life as usual and pretend like I haven&rsquo;t looked into the void.</p></li>
<li><p>&ldquo;Don&rsquo;t you see?&rdquo; (I&rsquo;m imagining the voice of Tim Keller here). &ldquo;Jesus Christ suffered the ultimate injustice so that we can be justified&mdash;and so that the world can know Justice.&rdquo; The Gospel is that the justice that was to be exacted on the murderer, the pimp, the politician, the single mother, the CEO, the checkout clerk and me&hellip; was placed on Jesus. Augh. Grace. Bitterness-melting, soul-lifting, hope-restoring Grace.</p></li>
<li><p>This is a sexy movement. Call+Response was about rock stars. The t-shirts are fashionable. We talk about entrepreneurial ventures and new business paradigms. People I meet are well-put together. But would I still be out here if this were a movement to end homelessness? How about adoption?  I wrestle with the question about whether it&rsquo;s about me wanting to be identified as a hip, socially-aware Christian, or if I&rsquo;m actually loving people and moving out from there.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Tonight my small group simply picked up trash around our Lake Merritt neighborhood. But I was talking with Tammie and Justin about how it should be the case that a neighborhood should be better off because Christians live there.</p>

<p>It is uncomfortable and we are getting nervous with the onset of darkness. We say hello to a woman at a street corner who merely mumbles back. Lazily, a police helicopter hovers in the skies.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
