<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: The Homeless | Finding Momentum]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/category/the-homeless/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-22T18:09:51-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Hao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A confession of a poverty of love]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/04/07/a-confession-of-a-poverty-of-love/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-07T16:15:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/04/07/a-confession-of-a-poverty-of-love</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The more I stay here the more I realize that I am <em>tired</em>, I am selfish, I am resentful. I am being changed&mdash;yes&mdash;by entering the lives of people in poverty and seeing the grace of being invited into their lives. Yes, I am learning from them a simple faith and a simple life. But it is difficult, and it&rsquo;s a place I do not know how to inhabit.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t know how to give grace to the people who drink on our doorsteps. I get resentful of people who have entitlement attitudes, and sense a creeping sense of dread of answering the doorbell to give food to folks who ask for it. I&rsquo;m tired of cleaning up human shit from our sidewalks and parking lot. I&rsquo;ve come to realize that my biggest fear is that I will annihilate myself in service, deeds, good works and on top of that <em>nothing will change.</em></p>

<p>Once Dave and I busted out onto the entranceway where homeless folks sleep on our doorstep because they were making a drunken racket. We yelled at them, hard: pointed at their beer bottles&mdash;<em>don&rsquo;t you ever drink on our doorstep again!</em>&mdash;gesticulating angrily, adrenaline flaring&mdash;<em>don&rsquo;t you lie to me! You can&rsquo;t sleep here anymore.</em> Yes, it was a power trip. No, we couldn&rsquo;t tolerate the noise and racket they were putting up. Yes, they were annoying the entire neighborhood. No, we weren&rsquo;t doing it very lovingly. Who&rsquo;s right? What was the right thing to do? Where was Jesus, and what would he have done?</p>

<p>They returned the next night.</p>

<p>I think we romanticize urban ministry sometimes, serving the poor, but have forgotten to count the cost. I often feel like that rich young ruler who, having heard Jesus' call to sell his possessions and leave a comfortable life, leaves sad. Because honestly, I do not know if I want to be here.</p>

<p>Lord, help me. Jesus, show me where you are <em>right here, right now</em>. I don&rsquo;t like dwelling in the tension of the brokenness of my neighborhood and the peace that is far away, already promised but not yet here. I know the answer is somewhere in hearing the inner voice of Love, in simply being a son and being Loved. Right now, I just feel stuck.</p>

<p>Last night I went back home to the quiet streets of Saratoga and I knew I couldn&rsquo;t go back. It didn&rsquo;t feel <em>real</em>. But I don&rsquo;t want to stay here either, swimming through the garbage in my soul and not knowing how to be well. Do I want to be well?, the Healer asks. Yes, but help my unbelief.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch us, protect us]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/01/18/watch-us-protect-us/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-18T18:42:59-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/01/18/watch-us-protect-us</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;re all holding hands on the street. Bear on my left, a stocky, grizzled Filipino dude wearing a hard expression under squinting eyes. Pancho on my right, a wiry black man with a thin face and a black &ldquo;OAKLAND&rdquo; beanie with big, gothic lettering. Cece is between the men, finishing a prayer: &ldquo;And keep us alllll&rdquo;&mdash;she draws out the word in her Native-American accent&mdash;&ldquo;safe from the <em>Devil</em>!&rdquo;</p>

<p>Amens all around.</p>

<p>Cece is direct, and I like that about her. She&rsquo;ll show up at the door and ask for a couple bucks for bus fare, or maybe a hot meal for the evening. No BS about your place burning to the ground, or needing travel fare to visit your newly-discovered relatives in Tuscon.</p>

<p>She reminds me of a bird, her beaked nose giving rise to sleepy eyes encased with gold wire-rimmed glasses. She waves her head about when she speaks, side-to-side like a pigeon&rsquo;s. You can see it particularly when she&rsquo;s off on one of her rambling episodes, going off about the weather, or about her Christmas, or the long bus route to Richmond, where she and her son Lamoine used to live in a shelter. Tonight&mdash;&ldquo;I got two kids with me&rdquo; &mdash; I am surprised to discover they are a little older.</p>

<p>Bear and Pancho, as far as I can tell, are Cece&rsquo;s friends, mid-twenties men dressed in black, hands in pockets and (I think) looking dangerous. I heat the food and find the three of them are waiting on the railing off to the side of our front entrance, where churchgoers are warily exiting the evening service. I drop off the food before Cece, who along with Pancho begin rifling through the contents.</p>

<p>Pancho slaps my hand in greeting and immediately informs me he used to sleep on the steps out here. &ldquo;You&rsquo;ve seen me around.&rdquo; Come to think about it, he does seem familiar.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Sheee-yit&rdquo; Bear exclaims with a smirk, &ldquo;Can I tell you a story? Some spirits live out here.&rdquo;</p>

<p>eveningtime, it is bitterly cold, he wakes to the sensation of being lifted and dragged. upward, upward he floats. he is flailing, someone, something has snatched him by the leg and he is now ten, twenty, thirty feet in the air (up by the tower, he gestures up overhead). he is let down and on his leg are finger marks, scratches, blood.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I ain&rsquo;t sleeping here no more.&rdquo; He stares out into the parking lot, a blank expression on his face. Bear has found another place to stay by the McDonalds on 17th.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah right, you can believe a lotta things,&rdquo; Pancho exclaims as he digs through a macaroni plate with his fingers. &ldquo;You was just crazy.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I believe that,&rdquo; I tell them. &ldquo;That stuff happens.&rdquo; Bear gives me a worried look, which turns to confusion.</p>

<p>Cece interjects, &ldquo;the <em>Devil</em> is REAL. He come to get me in my <em>dreams</em>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>she is a teenaged girl, though raised in a native american church out on 98th ave (her uncle was a priest) she left the Great Spirit to live the wild life, and oftentimes in her dreams she sees a figure, dark, red eyes, hovering. it is often hard to breathe and she has to try with all her strength to whisper the name of jesus, jesus, jesus. these days, the devil is after her nephew who presses a knife into her hands and tells her with a fearful smile: &ldquo;you&rsquo;ll need it, moms.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I believe that too,&rdquo; I say, and Cece smiles, looking around, satisfied.</p>

<p>Pancho knocks me on the forearm and chuckles, gesturing to Bear and Cece. &ldquo;Listen, I think the Devil ain&rsquo;t what we see in the movies with the <em>horns</em> and maybe the pitchfork. He&rsquo;s different.&rdquo; He doesn&rsquo;t elaborate.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah, that shit&rsquo;s real man, I ain&rsquo;t never coming out here again.&rdquo; Bear interjects.</p>

<p>&ldquo;The <em>Devil</em> is REAL. He come to me in my DREAMS!" Cece has gone off rambling again, her voice whiny and raspy and full of trembling fear. Her eyes dart about as her head bobs and her voice shrinks.</p>

<p>&ldquo;We don&rsquo;t gotta be afraid when we got God on our side.&rdquo; Pancho finishes.</p>

<p>We talk about Jesus. It&rsquo;s crazy, like a little church service.</p>

<p>Pancho: &ldquo;You know, I think Jesus beat the devil by going to the cross we don&rsquo;t gotta be afraid no more.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Me: &ldquo;I think that the name of Jesus is powerful and even the demons have got to submit to his name. I&rsquo;ve seen stuff like this happen.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Bear: &ldquo;For real?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Pancho: &ldquo;Oh <em>yeah</em>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Cece is still rambling.</p>

<p>Me: &ldquo;For real. You need to call on Jesus next time that stuff happens.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Bear: &ldquo;Listen man, can we have a prayer? I could use a prayer tonight.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Cece quiets down and nods her head.</p>

<p>Without a word, everybody extends a hand. Bear starts the prayer (&ldquo;Um I don&rsquo;t know how to do this man&rdquo;), Cece finishes us off (&ldquo;Aaaaa-man!&rdquo;). And amen.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Well this is hard.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2010/09/18/well-this-is-hard/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-18T22:29:11-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2010/09/18/well-this-is-hard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Man, God is totally wrecking me with this Betty thing.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been hard not to be cold to Betty after our repeated confrontations with her. To not let bitterness take root every time I feel like I see her act out of (what I believe to be) entitlement. And well, if I had to call it out, it <em>is</em> entitlement.</p>

<p>Monique is another lady that sleeps on the porch steps of the main church building. She urinates on herself, which leaves a  lingering stench on the porch for days. I&rsquo;m not sure if the incontinence has psychological or physiological roots, but she has refused to let us take her to a medical facility or shelter and asked us to leave her alone.</p>

<p>I realize more now that you think you can help the homeless, but in reality you don&rsquo;t know how. And because they keep pushing your boundaries, asking for more food, taking away at your time, you start to build resentment toward them, and dehumanizing them in your mind, which leads to bitterness.</p>

<p>We asked Monique to leave. <em>But the church is the house of prayer</em>, she told us. We told her that we just didn&rsquo;t know how to help her, and that she just couldn&rsquo;t sleep on the steps. <em>Why can&rsquo;t you just leave me alone and let me sleep there?</em> she asked. Good question. We could, theoretically, but it&rsquo;s a health risk, we told her. We have people come in and out of that building all the time and it&rsquo;s unacceptable that they have to smell it. <em>Fine, I&rsquo;m done with you all, nyah,</em> she protested and she gathered her belongings and stormed off.</p>

<p>I felt pretty guilty, because while you know that you can&rsquo;t help her, the other part of you feels like it should. And the other part of you knows that you&rsquo;re making her feel bad, that she can&rsquo;t help her incontinence, that she probably feels totally condemned and ashamed right now, and you should just leave her be.</p>

<p>Betty got into a shouting match with Rico, another homeless man in our building today while we were fixing them dinner. The two exchanged volleys and Betty demanded to call the policy while Rico asked her to leave. &ldquo;I need some safety, some protection&rdquo; she kept saying while Rico yelled profanities at her. We asked Rico to leave, and Betty was adamant about calling the cops because she felt threatened. So she did. And we sat around and felt like fools waiting for the cops to arrive. This is stupid, we told ourselves. We&rsquo;re being held hostage in our own place.</p>

<p>I saw Monique get up from sleeping in the parking lot this morning. She averted her eyes and wouldn&rsquo;t talk to me and made gestures to get up and leave, then moments later when my head was turned she put her bags back down. <em>We need this lot cleared today</em> I told her. When she wouldn&rsquo;t answer, I held my gaze longer until she averted her eyes, then turn around and walk away. Why do I do this? I&rsquo;m not sure. It sure is easier to do than offering her to use the restroom and cleaning up after her. It might have to do with my cognitive dissonance and fear in asking her to leave the day before then not wanting to enforce that boundary the next morning. And it could be that I enjoy feeling powerful. This is really hard.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not sure what God&rsquo;s doing in me through all this, but whatever it is, it&rsquo;s a lot more than I expected. Lord have mercy.</p>

<p>&mdash;</p>

<p>Edit: it&rsquo;s not all bad. I had a push-up pop afterwards and felt <em>much</em> better. I&rsquo;m not sure if Eric can say the same.</p>

<p>[flickr]<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5004495715/">http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5004495715/</a>[/flickr]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
