<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Cebu | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/categories/cebu/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-22T14:58:42-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell me what you want, and I'll give you my name]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2011/05/02/tell-me-what-you-want-and-ill-give-you-my-name/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-02T18:23:08-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2011/05/02/tell-me-what-you-want-and-ill-give-you-my-name</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>you have come to us in royal fashion, your slippers triumphantly slapping against gravel, your elegant fingers drumming against our windowpanes. you keep up a good pace, sir. you glide alongside our car and smile your patented, ringmaster smile. we watch you through one-way tinted glass and air-conditioned cabins. you are a curious specimen, a caged animal proudly loping the length of your alley.</p>

<p>at this point you would expect us to roll down our windows and expose our foreign skin, salivating mouths and lusting faces. you have girls for us, young ones whose virginities and sexual prowess you tout loudly, in broken phrases and sentences.</p>

<p>you know us; men who come through for innocent interludes and escapades. we want to feel flesh against ours and imagine the whispers of past loves. others will inhale deeply of the choking, snarling scent of lust, leaving inkdrops suspended in an ever-darkening pool of water.</p>

<p>you know how desperately we prefer to believe that these girls want us. we operate in fantasies. you provide them for us; you are the sultan of sex and the purveyor of pleasure. you feel powerful: the kick you get in offering the services of your women is unmatched by the wide-eyed grins of your customers. men now boys, they are pressing their faces against glass, drooling over shiny toys in storefront windows.</p>

<p>doggedly you chase after cars. or they run after you. your fingernails clack against the windowpanes and offer what you know your customers want, even if they don&rsquo;t willingly realize it yet. you need us. you love us. you resent us.</p>

<p>you resent us because we come from outside and we take your women. you&rsquo;ve seen how we use them like cheap change. but you too have participated.</p>

<p>you are not yourself. you grew up in a rusting city, its long, rambling corridors locking you in to your quarter-peso life. your life has never been easy. this is the only way you know how to survive in this rotting place. you know it too, but to see your girls as human is exquisitely painful. they hold a mirror to you and at the corners you can make out the crumbling images of your sister and your mother.</p>

<p>you pretend not to notice how the girls thicken after each session. quickly they become armored fortresses, silk buttresses over bronzed skin. it is too humid here; you cannot keep the patina from running down their shoulders.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric and Dr. Reuben]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2011/04/30/eric-and-dr-reuben/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-30T17:31:39-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2011/04/30/eric-and-dr-reuben</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5672837466/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5025/5672837466_8b4351e6e5.jpg" alt="Eric and Dr. Reuben by andrewhao" /></a><br/>
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5672837466/">Eric and Dr. Reuben</a>, a photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/">andrewhao</a> on Flickr.</p>

<p>Eric shakes hands with Dr. Reuben, the tribal chief of the Mamanwa village we visited on the island of Mindinao. We donated some funds to help the construction of a sanitation system.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On finding the place where the children have names]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2011/04/25/on-finding-the-place-where-the-children-have-names/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-25T08:04:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2011/04/25/on-finding-the-place-where-the-children-have-names</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It startled me because I actually felt it last night, the groaning of a city. Carlos' voice expressed it best, a wail that shook the walls: <em>Oh / how he loves us oh / how he loves us </em>and I felt like crying.</p>

<p>Tonight it was there again as we ran with the street kids. <em>Rugby boys</em>, they call them, the dirt-caked homeless kids of the city who sniff Rugby-brand glue to forget the pangs of hunger in their bellies. One of the boys has taken a liking to me and has a habit of flying at me and landing square on my back. He perches on the shoulders of another boy and launches up, up, and away&hellip;</p>

<p>I want to wail, but I can&rsquo;t be heard over the singing of men and women prophesying over the boys in Cebuano: <em>Your Father loves you; your Father has prepared a house for you where there will be no more pain</em>. <em>Hear the voice of your Father&hellip;</em> The boys are lying on the ground, resting, wrestling, festering, sweltering. They sing, too, poking each other in between refrains.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen this somewhere before. A dream? A crowded traffic circle, bright casino lights, the yellow cast of a sodium streetlamp, the sweltering heat. Twenty street kids, homeless men and women, an even-larger family surrounding them, and the songs. A song, their hearts, the traffic circle, the heart of the city, the children, the heart of the Father, their songs for the Father. They sing, I weep. I&rsquo;ve had this dream once before. Do the kids dream?</p>

<p>The congregation that we are with is also praying and listening. They are bent over next to each child as they whisper into their ears. A man not much younger than I translates for me: <em>he said thank you God for healing my brother</em>, or <em>that guy said thank you God for being with me another day</em>. I look over and Eric is cradling a girl who has fallen asleep in his arms. Zach is engrossed in a conversation with an old man. Ken carries a boy on his shoulders. We serve rice and pork stew slowly. I wield my ladle with slow, measured strokes in the broth. As it disappears I panic and pray harder.</p>

<p>What is this, Jesus? Something snaps and I want to cry; it&rsquo;s been so long since I&rsquo;ve felt this close to the Father. A dream buried from years ago resurfaces and wrecks me tonight. The city groans where the children sleep. I strain to listen; listen, can you hear? They are being birthed. Nobody wants to hold these children. Who will name them&mdash;the boy lands on my back and knocks the wind out of me&mdash;when we leave? Hurry, the children are arriving. Come and listen to their groans. The Father is close, and he has prepared them a home in his city.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pasil, a friend I never knew]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2011/04/23/pasil-a-friend-i-never-knew/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-23T17:30:29-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2011/04/23/pasil-a-friend-i-never-knew</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5670058698/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5266/5670058698_18165aaff4.jpg" alt="Pasil view" /></a></p>

<p>Yesterday we walked the slum village on the outskirts of town: Pasil. It was overwhelming: the crowded alleys bursting at the seams with noise, garbage, teeming life. The men are giving us resentful looks, sending us hostile messages with their eyes. The women are calling out to us&mdash;one grabs Zach&rsquo;s hand and walks with him hand-in-hand for a few steps. He recoils and she laughs, walking away with glimmering eyes.</p>

<p>Dave tells us to keep our eyes peeled down the alleys. I try to with sidelong glances, but it&rsquo;s hard to do so without appearing conspicuous. But I do and note that the dark side alleys run deep, giving testament to the sheer density and scope of this city within a city.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m intensely self-conscious. It&rsquo;s overwhelming; street kids hanging onto our pockets (we&rsquo;ve filled them with candy, and I find that my pocket has been sliced open already). They&rsquo;re everywhere, smothering me with their hands, fighting each other for the sweets. They&rsquo;re loud, intense, joyful, clamorous, direct (&ldquo;hey! give me money!&rdquo;). God, do I have a category for this?</p>

<p>I find myself walking through the alleys with a steely gaze, a half-smile plastered on my face. I&rsquo;ve experienced parts of this before, somewhere, but never all at once. I wonder how I&rsquo;m perceived. A Western male doesn&rsquo;t just traipse into this part of town without wanting something from it. Dave tells us that if we walked here at night, our reception would have been far more chilly.</p>

<p>Instead we get a blistering, smothering welcome, a tidal wave of heat, smog, clamoring hands, babies' cries, game show theme music, marching bands, basketball uniforms, fish rotting in the heat that you can almost feel them disintegrate as you walk by the markets. A drunken man I cannot see is singing in a karaoke shack, and a woman is giggling outside as she is playfully dragged back in; Ken presses more candy into my hands to give away. We barely squeeze by a couple of garbage trucks rumbling through a side street; a kid loses a sandal. A hand grabs mine, and I shake it off.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About to board]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2011/04/20/about-to-board/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-20T11:32:45-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhao.github.io/andrewhao/blog/2011/04/20/about-to-board</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m sitting in the terminal at SFO and about to board and it&rsquo;s finally hitting me&mdash;here we go. A few of you may have gotten this, but here&rsquo;s a quick recap of what I&rsquo;m going to spend the next few weeks doing:</p>

<p><strong>I'm going to Cebu</strong></p>

<p><strong>
</strong></p>

<p><strong>What: </strong>Missions trip to the Philippines with Regeneration, my church in Oakland.</p>

<p><strong>When: </strong>April 20th to May 3rd, 2011</p>

<p><strong>Why: </strong>Learn from anti-trafficking organizations &amp; support the local Church body.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5548186559/in/photostream/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5186/5548186559_70e047238c_m.jpg" alt="5548186559_70e047238c_m.jpg" /></a> <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5548765972/in/photostream/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5026/5548765972_4491753766_m.jpg" alt="5548765972_4491753766_m.jpg" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/2011-Support-Letter-Booklet.pdf">Read my full support letter (PDF)</a>.</p>

<p><strong>I&rsquo;d love your help!</strong></p>

<p><strong>
</strong></p>

<p><strong>Prayerfully:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Unity within our intern group, the wisdom to know how to work through conflicts and disagreements, and the prayerful hearts needed to daily equip ourselves with the Gospel.</p></li>
<li><p>Humility to move in a cross-cultural context, laying down our assumptions and being open toseeing the Kingdom there.</p></li>
<li><p>Spiritual protection as we move into an unfamiliar spiritual landscape.</p></li>
<li><p>For the Kingdom to continue to move powerfully in dark places amidst poverty, spiritual strongholds and oppression.</p></li>
<li><p>Joy! That the church body there would ooze Gospel joy.</p></li>
<li><p>That the staff at the Red Window Project would be strengthened with supernatural rest, community, faith, hope, &amp; love.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Please keep up with our prayer requests and trip updates on our blog: <a href="http://interns.regenerationweb.com/">http://interns.regenerationweb.com</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
