<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: God | Finding Momentum]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/category/god/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-18T19:13:26-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Hao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The soul]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2013/01/01/the-soul/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-01T15:29:42-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2013/01/01/the-soul</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Happy new year!</p>

<p>Last night I spent a good amount of time looking back at my journal and saw a few threads that ran through last year:</p>

<p>If 2011 was a year of risk-taking, then 2012, I&rsquo;ve summed up, was a building year, a year to build a rhythm and establish a flow. It was a full year at Blurb, commuting back and forth from SF. Keeping up the same routine at Regen. Stephen Ministry on Mondays, Circuit training Tuesdays, Wednesday mornings with Jeff, home group on Thursdays, Saturday morning runs, Sundays with Betty. Routine and rhythm. It can be good for you.</p>

<p>Knowing who I am, building a flow can be something to settle into but the risk is that I can get too comfortable.  But I found myself up against the reality that your ideals often have a hard time matching up to your reality. So on a serious note, last year was also the first year that I felt like I was just&hellip; <em>coasting</em>. And it felt horrible, the thought and feeling that the kind of life I should have been living should be filled with more risk, more Jesus + his presence. I&rsquo;m learning that I can oftentimes fall into routine and forget myself and why I&rsquo;m here.</p>

<p>There was a season &mdash; I remember it well &mdash; last year when I sat down and wrote down everything I was feeling &mdash; frustration with my life, honest doubts about my purpose and my faith and a slew of questions for God or Jesus or whoever it was that was overseeing my life. Life in Christ is filled with <em>joy</em>, right? Then why wasn&rsquo;t I feeling it? I was tempted to give it all up again.</p>

<p>The intersection of your faith and your daily life can disconnect sometimes, and things had derailed for a long time before I noticed it. The cynicism was subtle, but would crawl into things and inner dialogues. It would rebel against pat answers I saw people giving around me, or the cultural disconnects I&rsquo;d see between the church and Real Life, and a broken world.</p>

<p>The burnout was palpable, but here&rsquo;s the thing: it was something that I didn&rsquo;t do anything about. I kept up the same routines, held the same smiles and had the same answers. But inside there was a gnawing question that reappears from time to time: what is real about my life? Where was that sense that the world is on the brink of something glorious that I felt so often when I was younger&mdash;when things had a surety about them, and answers were more black and white, and joy was real because you were laughing, too? What about the intersection of dirt &amp; the divine, miracles I used to see, or evidence of the supernatural? Where does that stuff just <em>go</em> when you&rsquo;ve lived without them for so long?</p>

<p>Talking to Jeff, I was reminded that the times I felt <em>alive</em> in Christ were the times I was taking risks. So a lot of last year was about asking myself &mdash; where am I going? Where are places I can grow and risks that I can take? And there were a few themes: living in Oakland, identifying with the broken, friendships and brothers, youth &amp; community, silence &amp; solitude.</p>

<p>To be honest, a lot of that has not materialized, and a lot of that were gushy ideas lacking structure and thought and a strong heart.</p>

<p>God, I want that for this year. I want more faith, more experiences of your grace. I want courage to fight for people I love and defend the things I believe in (and vice versa). I want to run toward conflict instead of away from it. I want a stronger, more compassionate heart, and I want to run with people that show that too. But I mainly want to sense your nearness and know you with the familiarity of a son.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I did in 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2013/01/01/what-i-did-in-2012/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-01T15:17:31-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2013/01/01/what-i-did-in-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Competitively, this was a good year. I <a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/03/15/already-and-still-not-yet/">ran a 3:05 PR</a> at Napa (yay!), but missed Boston by seconds (argh).</p>

<p>I was <a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/05/07/seasons-shift/">frustrated with my plantar fasciitis</a>, but that gave me an opportunity to go into the swim and the bike and there were a lot of good memories doing long bike rides: Mt. Diablo + Mt. Tam with Bruce and friends. I also learned to swim in open water! Did my first <a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/07/15/golden-gate-tri-recap/">Olympic tri</a>, with a crazy current. Got a few friends to do a Tri for Fun. Come October, the PF began clearing out and I started hitting the trails again :)</p>

<p>2013 will be the year I attempt my first <a href="http://www.ar50mile.com/">50mi race</a>, and I&rsquo;m really looking forward to the training runs on the trails. I think I&rsquo;ll end up doing a half-Ironman in there somewhere. And perhaps another attempt at Boston in the fall. Nate&rsquo;s going to be training for Western States, and I figure if I run with that guy enough I should be in good shape&hellip;</p>

<p>2012 was the year I started getting serious about <a href="http://www.facebook.com/andrewhaophotography">photography</a>! I&rsquo;m finding that I&rsquo;m learning a lot more about the craft. Figuring out the technical details is important, but more than that, it&rsquo;s about working with subjects, making them feel at ease. It&rsquo;s about finding light and keeping your eyes open always and going with your gut. It&rsquo;s about taking risks and trying new poses and settings. Wedding-wise, it&rsquo;s about planning, preparation and being on your toes. I have a lot to learn still, and I&rsquo;m excited about 2013&rsquo;s new assignments.</p>

<p>Wejoinin was kind of on the back burner but Hsiu-Fan and I are nearing the completion of a Rails 3 upgrade. More on that soon on my <a href="http://www.g9labs.com">technical blog</a>.</p>

<p>I took trips to Portland, LA, and even South Carolina.</p>

<p>I went to more than a few weddings and saw quite a few friends get hitched. Congratulations!</p>

<p>And&hellip; I started dating again. The feeling&rsquo;s a little surreal, but I like her a lot :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finding reason for thanks]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/11/23/finding-reason-for-thanks/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T19:11:52-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/11/23/finding-reason-for-thanks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/8184502276/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8210/8184502276_7dcb9b2040.jpg" alt="Up and over" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sitting at Coffee Society here back home,  journaling and feeling generally overwhelmed by God&rsquo;s goodness. I&rsquo;m not sure when I felt it, but it might have been yesterday&rsquo;s slow, rambling run through the foothills from pre-dawn dusk to midmorning cool, or experiencing the long-anticipated togetherness of a Thanksgiving meal. Or maybe it was just hanging with Annie over lunch and being able to feel like a big brother again, or that my dad just dropped a new iPhone in my lap&hellip; just like that. I&rsquo;m seeing movement in my life, and things feel like they&rsquo;re coming together. I just had the thought&hellip; I can&rsquo;t deserve much of this. Things shouldn&rsquo;t be this good.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been realizing lately there&rsquo;s this dichotomy in how I see myself &mdash; on one hand, I have a very outside-in view of myself, painfully aware of others' perceptions of myself and always trying hard to do things that create a polished image (see: <a href="http://www.enneagraminstitute.com/typethree.asp#.ULA2NeOe_ls">Enneagram 3</a>, of which I&rsquo;m becoming increasingly convinced of). I can experience myself as a high-performer, a compassionate human, and generally rad dude.</p>

<p>Then there&rsquo;s the other part of myself that&rsquo;s pretty painfully aware of my flaws and shortcomings. It knows my hiding places and how often I can retreat to them&hellip; the places in myself that I experience fears and insecurities.</p>

<p>The achiever in me lives in fear of failure, the sense that things can&rsquo;t always be this good and I can&rsquo;t enjoy good things because I&rsquo;m bound to eff things up, or the sneaking suspicion that something catastrophic is around the corner. The hidden places in me are always wary of being exposed, or worried that I won&rsquo;t live up to expectations (whose?).</p>

<p>The longer I live the more I&rsquo;m realizing that these two parts of myself are redeemed by the Gospel. In the Gospel I can acknowledge my imposter and broken self. In the Gospel I begin with the fact that I deserved no good gifts, but then I am given something truly Good. It grounds me and humbles me, and most of all it allows me to <a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/01/14/foreword/">yield</a> and experience gifts for what they are&hellip; and allow myself to savor the significance of this delight: that I&rsquo;m simply his son, and he&rsquo;s a good Father to me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Say to my soul]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/05/20/say-to-my-soul/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-20T10:00:16-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/05/20/say-to-my-soul</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Through your own merciful dealings with me, O Lord my God, tell me what you are to me. Say to my soul, I am your salvation. Say it so that I can hear it. My heart is listening, Lord; open the ears of my heart and say to my soul, I am your salvation. Let me run towards this voice and seize hold of you. Do not hide your face from me: let me die so that I may see it, for not to see it would be death to me indeed.</p>

<p>— St. Augustine, <em>Confessions</em></p>

<p>What I love is that Augustine asks God to move toward him &mdash; <em>Say to my soul, I am your salvation</em>. I&rsquo;m listening, he says, but I need you to speak it to me so it resonates with my soul.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seasons' shift]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/05/07/seasons-shift/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-07T09:33:19-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/05/07/seasons-shift</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I feel like seasons are changing, not just in the air but through my life. I&rsquo;m outdoors more often, laughing more, more <em>okay</em> with things being stuck, or in-between, or just not formed yet.</p>

<p>The plantar fasciitis is still there, and not being able to run has been frustrating to say the least, but I&rsquo;ve been enjoying bike rides and swims. Summer is in the air, and a part of me is stretching and yawning and settling in to it. One of my favorite feelings is being at home with friends on a warm evening with the windows open, full after a shared meal, listening to a George Strait song and chatting about whatever. Those nights I go to bed and think to myself, <em>I&rsquo;m happy. God is good. I have been given much.</em></p>

<p>I thought the same thing about my family&hellip; we Skyped for a bit last week and I wonder why I&rsquo;m not more in touch with them more often when there&rsquo;s clearly a lot of love between us. I have been given much. And this is kind of awkward because they all read this blog (hi Mom!).</p>

<p>Those who sow in tears will reap with songs of joy, said the psalmist, from <a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/10/11/on-the-other-side-of-autumn/">autumn</a> to winter to spring to summer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
