<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Social Justice | Finding Momentum]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/category/social-justice/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-19T19:54:05-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Hao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First fires]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/11/08/first-fires/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-08T09:56:28-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/11/08/first-fires</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/6325341766/"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6235/6325341766_6102cb11da.jpg" alt="Occupy Oakland" /></a></p>

<p>There was some sort of relief, I decided, in having set foot in the Occupy camp and finding it quiet. Wednesday, Oakland was paraded across the global consciousness as national news media displayed scenes of urban warfare, with ghostly images of terror-stricken faces sent helter-skelter across the airwaves. Zach showed me the frontpage of the BBC website (<em>Occupy Oakland protestors disrupt city</em>) and made a cutting remark about how the protestors were making fools of themselves on global media and how Oakland was going to suffer. The next morning we all got worried emails and well-intentioned text messages from friends and family: <em>hey, you doing okay? </em>to which we&rsquo;d respond with sheepish grace that no, we weren&rsquo;t part of the protests and no, Oakland hadn&rsquo;t burnt to the ground. Yet.</p>

<p>That Saturday we walked the downtown Oakland area and stood among the protestors in Frank Ogawa Plaza and I tried taking it in, inhaling the hot, musty mess, sidling up to the sleeping giant. I&rsquo;m not quite sure what I had expected: chaos, rowdier citizens, widespread aggression and disquiet? Instead we found sleepy-eyed campers, dreadlocked ponytails, and hand-drawn raggedy signs. You could smell the weed from blocks away. Nate confirmed the portable toilets were overflowing and rancid.</p>

<p>Self-conscious, I realized later, is how I feel, not knowing how to identify with this spectacle. My sentiments about the whole thing are less of explosive outrage than subtle helplessness. Here I was, middle-class and Asian-American, walking through the tent city of the dispossessed, and I felt both a repulsion to the sideshow and an isolating sense of guilt knowing that I was a stranger to racial and economic injustice.</p>

<p>We bumped into Bonnie on the way over, a homeless friend of ours who makes appearances often at the church. "You should have been there, they had us <em>cornered</em>&ldquo; she exclaimed with wide eyes, giggling in her two-toned accent. <em>&rdquo;</em>Pohh-leece got us trapped up on both sides. I got some of that gas stuff in me, and it make you tear up real bad."</p>

<p>Bonnie had stayed with the protestors for a couple of days. &ldquo;It was like a <em>war</em>, let me tell you, and the sad thing&rdquo;&mdash;her voice dropped to a whisper&mdash;&ldquo;is nobody can help you.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I wondered what Bonnie must have felt; my mind replayed scenes from a Free Speech Movement documentary I once watched at Cal. Observe: an aerial shot from what must have been a tall building or a helicopter, riot police on either ends of the block, smoke rising from the street in lazy, elegant arcs. Notice: a couple of figures limp for cover, fumbling to cover their eyes. See: grainy film, shot black and white, <em>viva</em> free speech &amp; the cause of justice, <em>fin</em>.</p>

<p>So I was relieved to find Frank Ogawa Plaza rather pleasant. A tent city had risen, built on fresh-laid straw, with hypnotic Native American drumming drifting through camp. Smiling stoners sat cross-legged in a corner beneath a tarp and gazed intently into the distance. A mini-rally proceeded in another, where a megaphone-toting Latina woman was organizing that afternoon&rsquo;s march on Wells Fargo<em>. </em>In other words, it was amusingly like college. We opened our burritos and ate on the steps of the City Hall amphitheater and watched the tent city pulse as it awoke.</p>

<p>The Tuesday night that things got bad, I was running the lake under the assured hum of news helicopters, but I couldn&rsquo;t tell you if things were out of the ordinary. It was strange, I suppose because I had imagined that should my city go down in flames, everybody should know about it and share in the panic and outrage. Women pushed murmuring babies by in fancy strollers. The wind whispered through the grove of trees around the lake&rsquo;s finger-bend. Runners grunted to each other, pushing gravel through the ground. Starlight &amp; Lake Merritt&rsquo;s necklace, swan, geese, &amp; ghetto birds all there to witness war, but somebody had forgotten to remind me.</p>

<p>Saturday, Kylan and Betty and I walked up Telegraph and prayed for Occupy Oakland and I felt rather foolish for not knowing what exactly to pray for. I remembered Silvia&rsquo;s weight of sadness, when she showed up and wound up feeling lost and helpless and hurt for the brokenness of the world she lived in and the chaos unfolding around her and the need for Jesus to show up right there and <em>occupy</em>&hellip;</p>

<p>Proverbs 29 was a comfort, the words breathing and expanding in my thoughts:</p>

<blockquote><p><em>When the righteous increase, the people rejoice but when the wicked rule, people groan</em></p></blockquote>

<p>and,</p>

<blockquote><p><em>The poor and the oppressor meet together, the LORD gives light to them both</em></p></blockquote>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/6325344666/"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6040/6325344666_68f59b38d3.jpg" alt="Occupy Oakland" /></a></p>

<p>Earlier that morning I dreamt we were evacuating our city in long single-file strands. We wound through our neighborhood, and I remember standing in our living room arguing with Justin whether we should load this or that couch into the U-Haul. People shuffled by outside in colorless clothing, feeling here and gone at the same time. Children whispered to each other in shy, hushed tones. The helicopters were there again, whirling lazily, watching overhead. In that moment I knew (though a dream) the question had become not how we would leave, but whether we would stay.</p>

<p>I woke far too early, thirsty, trying to recall how the air felt against my cheeks: <em>thwup thwup thwup thwup thwup.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bits and pieces of orphaned conversations]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/08/18/bits-and-pieces-of-orphaned-conversations/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-18T23:56:13-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/08/18/bits-and-pieces-of-orphaned-conversations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My nephew, he&rsquo;s the one in Afghanistan. Sometimes I wish I could take his place because if I go&hellip; <em>(silence)</em> it doesn&rsquo;t matter.</p>

<p>Listen, I ain&rsquo;t gonna lie about it. I&rsquo;m an alcoholic. I don&rsquo;t drink because I&rsquo;m sad. I drink because I liiiiiiike drinking.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t know if I can trust you anymore, man. You lost my trust.</p>

<p>Hey, can I get a flashlight? There&rsquo;s someone behind these bushes.</p>

<p>You got a bite to eat? Listen man I just need a bite. Did I come too late? What time is it?</p>

<p>I been all around Oakland, and this is the safest place to be.</p>

<p>Get out. You can&rsquo;t just come in here and help yourself to our food.</p>

<p>Is she breathing? Yes? Okay let me call the ambulance.</p>

<p>Listen man, I feel hurt I don&rsquo;t know <em>who&rsquo;s</em> making those accusations about me but I&rsquo;m telling you I ain&rsquo;t selling the food. It hurts me that they&rsquo;re saying these things.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s Essie&rsquo;s birthday today! <em>(singing of birthday songs).</em></p>

<p>I told you not to sleep on these steps but I saw you here last night.</p>

<p>Me and her are gonna get married on the 14th.</p>

<p>Rico thinks he&rsquo;s gonna die. I think he&rsquo;s given up.</p>

<p>Rico&rsquo;s been doing real well lately. I think he&rsquo;s turning a corner.</p>

<p>Listen man can I say a prayer for us?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A confession of a poverty of love]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/04/07/a-confession-of-a-poverty-of-love/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-07T16:15:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/04/07/a-confession-of-a-poverty-of-love</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The more I stay here the more I realize that I am <em>tired</em>, I am selfish, I am resentful. I am being changed&mdash;yes&mdash;by entering the lives of people in poverty and seeing the grace of being invited into their lives. Yes, I am learning from them a simple faith and a simple life. But it is difficult, and it&rsquo;s a place I do not know how to inhabit.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t know how to give grace to the people who drink on our doorsteps. I get resentful of people who have entitlement attitudes, and sense a creeping sense of dread of answering the doorbell to give food to folks who ask for it. I&rsquo;m tired of cleaning up human shit from our sidewalks and parking lot. I&rsquo;ve come to realize that my biggest fear is that I will annihilate myself in service, deeds, good works and on top of that <em>nothing will change.</em></p>

<p>Once Dave and I busted out onto the entranceway where homeless folks sleep on our doorstep because they were making a drunken racket. We yelled at them, hard: pointed at their beer bottles&mdash;<em>don&rsquo;t you ever drink on our doorstep again!</em>&mdash;gesticulating angrily, adrenaline flaring&mdash;<em>don&rsquo;t you lie to me! You can&rsquo;t sleep here anymore.</em> Yes, it was a power trip. No, we couldn&rsquo;t tolerate the noise and racket they were putting up. Yes, they were annoying the entire neighborhood. No, we weren&rsquo;t doing it very lovingly. Who&rsquo;s right? What was the right thing to do? Where was Jesus, and what would he have done?</p>

<p>They returned the next night.</p>

<p>I think we romanticize urban ministry sometimes, serving the poor, but have forgotten to count the cost. I often feel like that rich young ruler who, having heard Jesus' call to sell his possessions and leave a comfortable life, leaves sad. Because honestly, I do not know if I want to be here.</p>

<p>Lord, help me. Jesus, show me where you are <em>right here, right now</em>. I don&rsquo;t like dwelling in the tension of the brokenness of my neighborhood and the peace that is far away, already promised but not yet here. I know the answer is somewhere in hearing the inner voice of Love, in simply being a son and being Loved. Right now, I just feel stuck.</p>

<p>Last night I went back home to the quiet streets of Saratoga and I knew I couldn&rsquo;t go back. It didn&rsquo;t feel <em>real</em>. But I don&rsquo;t want to stay here either, swimming through the garbage in my soul and not knowing how to be well. Do I want to be well?, the Healer asks. Yes, but help my unbelief.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Justice and me]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/03/18/justice-and-me/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-18T01:31:15-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/03/18/justice-and-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m wrestling a lot these days with the idea of Justice and what it looks like to be a Christian&mdash;and a human&mdash;in the midst of it.</p>

<p>This week, the <a href="http://interns.regenerationweb.com">interns and I</a> have been at the <a href="http://www.notforsalecampaign.org/news/topic/investigator-academy/">Not for Sale Academy</a> receiving training on human trafficking before we head out to the Philippines in April. I&rsquo;m feeling a lot of heaviness, hearing stories about people held captive under another&rsquo;s power.</p>

<p>A few things I&rsquo;ve been chewing on:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The perversion of masculinity, a fascination (and insecurity) with power, control &amp; ego versus the created Ideal: protective, disciplined, self-sacrificing, Christlike.</p></li>
<li><p>I&rsquo;m nervous about entering darkness; the thought of walking a red-light district scares me. Can I handle it? Also: thoughts on continual prayer as we walk through the shadows. We need to pray to survive.</p></li>
<li><p>I&rsquo;m glad I&rsquo;m going with this group of guys.</p></li>
<li><p>It&rsquo;s okay to feel pain. I&rsquo;m wondering if I even want to be identified with this movement because of the heaviness surrounding it. I&rsquo;m realizing that maybe the pain of the world is what God wants us to feel&mdash;to grieve alongside the broken and the powerless and to be saddened by the injustice in the world.</p></li>
<li><p>On the other side, I&rsquo;m thankful that our God is a God of vengeance and justice. He promises to repay for evil. That is very. comforting. Honestly, I&rsquo;m not sure how I would deal with the brokenness without an Absolute, a Good framework.</p></li>
<li><p>But honestly, I mostly want to turn and go back to life as usual and pretend like I haven&rsquo;t looked into the void.</p></li>
<li><p>&ldquo;Don&rsquo;t you see?&rdquo; (I&rsquo;m imagining the voice of Tim Keller here). &ldquo;Jesus Christ suffered the ultimate injustice so that we can be justified&mdash;and so that the world can know Justice.&rdquo; The Gospel is that the justice that was to be exacted on the murderer, the pimp, the politician, the single mother, the CEO, the checkout clerk and me&hellip; was placed on Jesus. Augh. Grace. Bitterness-melting, soul-lifting, hope-restoring Grace.</p></li>
<li><p>This is a sexy movement. Call+Response was about rock stars. The t-shirts are fashionable. We talk about entrepreneurial ventures and new business paradigms. People I meet are well-put together. But would I still be out here if this were a movement to end homelessness? How about adoption?  I wrestle with the question about whether it&rsquo;s about me wanting to be identified as a hip, socially-aware Christian, or if I&rsquo;m actually loving people and moving out from there.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Tonight my small group simply picked up trash around our Lake Merritt neighborhood. But I was talking with Tammie and Justin about how it should be the case that a neighborhood should be better off because Christians live there.</p>

<p>It is uncomfortable and we are getting nervous with the onset of darkness. We say hello to a woman at a street corner who merely mumbles back. Lazily, a police helicopter hovers in the skies.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slavery Today (Infographic)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/03/13/slavery-today-infographic/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-13T10:27:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/03/13/slavery-today-infographic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5523317386/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5134/5523317386_1b2c6967c4.jpg" alt="Slavery Today Infographic (Freedom Sunday)" /></a><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5522731659/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5092/5522731659_4bfa77761f.jpg" alt="Slavery Today Infographic (Freedom Sunday)" /></a></p>

<p>An infographic for <a href="http://www.freedomsunday.org/">Freedom Sunday</a> at <a href="http://www.regenerationweb.com">Regeneration</a>. <a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/Slavery-Today-Flyer.pdf">Download as PDF</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
