<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: family | Finding Momentum]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/category/family/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-19T19:54:05-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Hao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell your loved ones]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2016/11/19/tell-your-loved-ones/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-19T18:54:30-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2016/11/19/tell-your-loved-ones</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The sudden death of a friend&rsquo;s father this past week had us all reeling &ndash;
on top of an already-difficult 2016, this really hurt.</p>

<p>Annie and I made our way to the funeral home
this morning and stood in the crowded overflow room. The service was
packed to the brim with Taiwanese aunties and uncles I&rsquo;d have expected
to bump into church back when I was a kid.</p>

<p>Though I only understood about a third of what was being said, I could
sense the love in the room &ndash; the collective mourning of a community that
had stuck together for decades and coming to grips with a loss of their
own.</p>

<p>I couldn&rsquo;t help but thing that this friend&rsquo;s father was my own &ndash; he was
a Taiwanese man, born to a plain existence in Taiwan but
immigrated to the US for graduate school in search of a better life. His
story of finding centering and solace in his friendships in the Bay Area
is a story that many of our own families can tell.</p>

<p>We stood outside the burial plot, wind and rain whipping against our
faces, and watched him be lowered into the ground. Shivering, I craved beef broth,
the kind boiled sweet-hot with ox tail and tendon and
overflowing with spices and cilantro.</p>

<p>I couldn&rsquo;t help but think imagine I would be here with my own dad one day.
For a second, I panicked, feeling like I needed to make a
phone call, waiting past the dial tone to hear his voice on the line.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
