<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Family | Finding Momentum]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/category/family/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-22T18:11:25-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Hao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finding reason for thanks]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/11/23/finding-reason-for-thanks/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T19:11:52-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/11/23/finding-reason-for-thanks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/8184502276/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8210/8184502276_7dcb9b2040.jpg" alt="Up and over" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sitting at Coffee Society here back home,  journaling and feeling generally overwhelmed by God&rsquo;s goodness. I&rsquo;m not sure when I felt it, but it might have been yesterday&rsquo;s slow, rambling run through the foothills from pre-dawn dusk to midmorning cool, or experiencing the long-anticipated togetherness of a Thanksgiving meal. Or maybe it was just hanging with Annie over lunch and being able to feel like a big brother again, or that my dad just dropped a new iPhone in my lap&hellip; just like that. I&rsquo;m seeing movement in my life, and things feel like they&rsquo;re coming together. I just had the thought&hellip; I can&rsquo;t deserve much of this. Things shouldn&rsquo;t be this good.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been realizing lately there&rsquo;s this dichotomy in how I see myself &mdash; on one hand, I have a very outside-in view of myself, painfully aware of others' perceptions of myself and always trying hard to do things that create a polished image (see: <a href="http://www.enneagraminstitute.com/typethree.asp#.ULA2NeOe_ls">Enneagram 3</a>, of which I&rsquo;m becoming increasingly convinced of). I can experience myself as a high-performer, a compassionate human, and generally rad dude.</p>

<p>Then there&rsquo;s the other part of myself that&rsquo;s pretty painfully aware of my flaws and shortcomings. It knows my hiding places and how often I can retreat to them&hellip; the places in myself that I experience fears and insecurities.</p>

<p>The achiever in me lives in fear of failure, the sense that things can&rsquo;t always be this good and I can&rsquo;t enjoy good things because I&rsquo;m bound to eff things up, or the sneaking suspicion that something catastrophic is around the corner. The hidden places in me are always wary of being exposed, or worried that I won&rsquo;t live up to expectations (whose?).</p>

<p>The longer I live the more I&rsquo;m realizing that these two parts of myself are redeemed by the Gospel. In the Gospel I can acknowledge my imposter and broken self. In the Gospel I begin with the fact that I deserved no good gifts, but then I am given something truly Good. It grounds me and humbles me, and most of all it allows me to <a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/01/14/foreword/">yield</a> and experience gifts for what they are&hellip; and allow myself to savor the significance of this delight: that I&rsquo;m simply his son, and he&rsquo;s a good Father to me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[30,000 feet at eleven]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/06/09/30000-feet-at-eleven/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-09T01:33:11-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/06/09/30000-feet-at-eleven</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>I&rsquo;m not afraid of dying</em>. I&rsquo;m surprised by the thought flitting across my mind as my plane takes off. Were we to plunge into the California coast as the scene used to play out in my imagination, I&rsquo;d be ready for that.</p>

<p>I had a backwards-sort of feeling tonight as I entered the airport, breezing through the security lines and arriving at my gate much too early. Justin and Frank had dropped me off and gone to In &lsquo;n Out without me.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m going home to Pasadena. Or rather, I&rsquo;m going to see my family in Pasadena, with Annie&rsquo;s graduation being the reason for celebration. Going home means something different these days. Is it the house you grew up in? Is about seeing your family, your friends? Is it neon-lit boba shops, or the wideness of De Anza Boulevard or Calabasas Park with the ghost stories or the panicky feeling of waking up realizing you&rsquo;ve overslept first period or junior or senior prom from howlongago&mdash; and the exhilaration of pulling off a spectacular field show or the happy sensation of rolling up to a full dining table exploding with Taiwanese foods? Yes, yes, and yes.</p>

<p>I have a memory where I am dropping off my parents at SFO. They are leaving for China, my sisters are still undergrads in San Diego. I am seeing Sarah at the time; she stands to my left as we wave our good-byes to them from across the glassed security walls. And that&rsquo;s when it hits, a sudden blue-ness, a feeling of being gone, or that finally, I am on my own. I wonder if that&rsquo;s what it feels like to be grown-up. All the older folks in Stephen Ministry tell about loved ones passing away, spouses divorcing, buddies moving across the country for a job, or spouse, or to take care of a relative. It&rsquo;s a fact (it&rsquo;s so true that you may surprise yourself because you don&rsquo;t understand it yet), the people you grow to treasure and love will leave you, and that leaving-ness is a sensation that startled me that day. Perhaps it&rsquo;s just as true that I was unique in experiencing it so late in my life.</p>

<p>In that memory, we duck in to the Sharper Image store to play with the massage chairs. The rollers playfully tug and push and pull at my calves and lower back, and I stare hard at the remote, squirming, barely making out the buttons, fighting back stupid tears. Hold it together man. C'mon, I&rsquo;m self-talking. Pull yourself together.</p>

<p>But it&rsquo;s a backward feeling because tonight I&rsquo;m flying home to my family. I am excited to see everybody again. I&rsquo;m proud of my sister. I&rsquo;m glad to get out of Oakland. I&rsquo;m feeling a bit more courageous. It merely took time.</p>

<p>Later on the plane, I&rsquo;m dozing off when another memory startles me: Shortly after my dad gave me my first computer somewhere in the fifth grade, I convinced my mom to buy me a word processor to install on it. I was a bookish kid then (thankfully!), and always had my nose buried in a novel. I had just finished reading some Crichton book&mdash;<em>Airframe</em> I believe&mdash;and wrote a story basically verbatim from the book about a plane crashing in the Pacific. In it, I describe in painstaking detail the panic of the passengers, the luggage flying about the compartment, the sound the latches made when they flipped open, what exactly the pilot would say into the intercom&hellip; which was whatever Mr. Crichton would have said in his novel. I titled the piece <em>The Final Flight of Flight 738</em> or something equally dramatic to an eleven-year-old. But the most clear part of the memory was when my dad saw that I was writing something that Saturday morning: I saw a blend of curiosity and pride light up his face. &ldquo;Here. Let me see it,&rdquo; he had said, moving toward me, reaching for the printout in my hands.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seasons' shift]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/05/07/seasons-shift/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-07T09:33:19-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/05/07/seasons-shift</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I feel like seasons are changing, not just in the air but through my life. I&rsquo;m outdoors more often, laughing more, more <em>okay</em> with things being stuck, or in-between, or just not formed yet.</p>

<p>The plantar fasciitis is still there, and not being able to run has been frustrating to say the least, but I&rsquo;ve been enjoying bike rides and swims. Summer is in the air, and a part of me is stretching and yawning and settling in to it. One of my favorite feelings is being at home with friends on a warm evening with the windows open, full after a shared meal, listening to a George Strait song and chatting about whatever. Those nights I go to bed and think to myself, <em>I&rsquo;m happy. God is good. I have been given much.</em></p>

<p>I thought the same thing about my family&hellip; we Skyped for a bit last week and I wonder why I&rsquo;m not more in touch with them more often when there&rsquo;s clearly a lot of love between us. I have been given much. And this is kind of awkward because they all read this blog (hi Mom!).</p>

<p>Those who sow in tears will reap with songs of joy, said the psalmist, from <a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/10/11/on-the-other-side-of-autumn/">autumn</a> to winter to spring to summer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yie yie in the light of the sun]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/04/15/yie-yie-in-the-light-of-the-sun/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-15T16:02:11-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/04/15/yie-yie-in-the-light-of-the-sun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/6568458747/"><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7027/6568458747_9c0dfcd0b7.jpg" alt="DSC_0243" /></a></p>

<p>He looks into me with soft eyes, and sings in Mandarin: &ldquo;Look into His face / and your worries will disappear with the light of the sun&rdquo;.</p>

<p>He&rsquo;s not bad for his age. Apparently he sings in the elderly folks' choir at his church. &ldquo;He&rsquo;s the only one who can sing!&rdquo; laughs my dad.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re sitting in a hotel restaurant, filled to the brim with Christmastime muzak and chatty customers. I feel the restaurant growing quieter as he continues to sing, a throaty baritone voice growing more confident as I grow more self-conscious at the same time.</p>

<p>My yie yie (爺爺)&rsquo;s eyes are becoming dimmer with the years, I can see, hiding under bushy, busy white eyebrows and thick, leathery suntanned skin. Coming over with the KMT from the mainland was tough on him. My dad would tell me of Yie yie&rsquo;s extended military deployments in Vietnam, Korea, and Japan. His past is a storied and shrouded one, working for Chinese intelligence doing radio surveillance. After splitting with his unit during the upheavals of the Revolution, he came to Taiwan to work again for KMT intelligence, eavesdropping on the very same people he used to work with.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Japan was especially nice&rdquo;, Yie yie recounts with a smile. He was stationed with US troops on a military base, and he tells us stories of watching a movie every night, eating great food. He is a young man, still. He keeps a journal of each movie he sees, and the journal grows thick over the year. A mischievous smile grows over Yie yie&rsquo;s face as he recounts how he&rsquo;d smuggle hard-boiled eggs from the cafeteria in his pants pockets, only to spill them all over the basketball court in a pickup game hours later.</p>

<p>How old is he in those years?, I wonder. He couldn&rsquo;t have been much older than I am now. Does he enjoy Coke? How about mangoes? I imagine him writing his wife, asking about my father as a young boy. The world is a different place. He tells a story of losing close friends in a Vietcong mortar attack in Vietnam, and his eyes grow misty. Smoke rises from the jungles, and I wonder if he ever wonders why he, and by extension my father and myself, are spared.</p>

<p>My dad would never get to see his dad much during those years, and when he came back, most of his memories of Yie yie were of an ill-tempered man he&rsquo;d tend to hide from. But something happened in the intervening years after Yie yie came home for good. He softened out. Jesus got to him.</p>

<p>I wanted to come here to find myself in Yie yie and his life. I want to know his strength and determination to live, and realize that there is much more beneath the surface of the man that I&rsquo;ve only seen sitting down, smiling and laughing. What keeps a man rooted even when he is swept about?</p>

<p>Right now, Yie yie&rsquo;s singing Psalm 23. &ldquo;Can you remember the words?&rdquo; my dad asks as Yie yie struggles through the verses. The Lord is my shepherd. He leads me through quiet waters. I fear no evil.</p>

<p>He can remember them just fine.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gong gong & puo puo]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/01/23/gong-gong-puo-puo/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-23T10:04:35-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/01/23/gong-gong-puo-puo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My grandfather (ah gong, or 外公, but we call him gong gong), driven by winds of Communist change, arrived in Taiwan in the 1940s. He was a Fuzhou businessman, 26 at the time. He was a businessman, relatively wealthy and educated, and fled from the incoming Communists.</p>

<p>He met my grandmother (ah ma, or 外媽 &mdash; but we&rsquo;ve grown up calling her puo puo) while they both worked as schoolteachers at the same elementary school.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Your ah gong was a handsome man&rdquo; my grandmother says with a chuckle and a glimmer in her eye. She is dignified, ladylike, and precise. She bears eyes with depth, holding her teacup with deliberate old-world delicacy. My early memories are sprinkled with her constant presence in our house, making fantastic food and reading me chinese fables for bedtime stories.</p>

<p>They met in the years in between the world wars, when the world was changing. My grandma was native Taiwanese, telling me about the world she grew up in, hearing American bombers fly overhead, when alarms would sound and they would have to head to the mountains to hide in the hills. Taiwan was different then, they were raised to believe they were Japanese.</p>

<p>They fell in love, but they don&rsquo;t speak much about it nowadays. I wonder how it was back then. She was trained as a schoolteacher, and he must have been good with the kids given his gregarious charm. It&rsquo;s not hard to imagine why they fell in love, but how? I wonder if they can still remember.</p>

<p>These days, they live in Taipei in a modern apartment, paneled in marble and dark wood. His hands tremble when they reach for the dishes on the table. She reaches for the dish and steadies it for him. After each meal he silently shuffles to the couch and picks his teeth with a toothpick and looks out the window at the glassy beams of the Taipei 101 tower.</p>

<p>Her family would have nothing to do with him. He was an outsider, one of the KMT occupiers. Stories ran rampant about KMT men looking for Taiwanese wives while keeping a wife back in China. What did my great-grandfather think of him? Did they ever meet? Or did he forbid their love from the outside?</p>

<p>So they eloped.</p>

<p>Annie asks if puo-puo gets tired of cooking for us. My dad laughs. &ldquo;I bet she loves it that we&rsquo;re here. She loves to cook.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The spread is enormous. Taro fish ball soup, fresh steamed fish from the market, boiled chicken, dumplings, radish salad, an array of steamed vegetables and guavas and wax apples for dessert. We lay there after each meal, stunned and deliriously happy.</p>

<p>My mom would tell me about how in the years down the road after their marriage, gong-gong would eventually win over my grandmother&rsquo;s family with his kindness, generosity, and charm and twinkle in his eye. I wonder what it was like, a slow, gradual warming, a reconciliation that may have taken years to mend.</p>

<p>My uncle calls us when we&rsquo;re there, asking if they want to come with them on their upcoming vacation to Japan. Puo-puo hesitates, smiling a bit, thinking. When she is thinking, she knits her brow and blinks slowly. It&rsquo;s her reserved nature that defines her elegance, I decide. But she is like a wall, difficult to read. I want to ask her about her young love.</p>

<p>&ldquo;No,&rdquo; she finally says, &ldquo;I should stay here. It&rsquo;s cold in Japan. And I need to be with your dad.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Later as we sit around the living room sharing our hopes for the new year (my dad puts us through these things) gong-gong makes an innocent face and tells us that his hope is that &ldquo;your puo-puo should visit Japan and get out of the house and not have to take care of me.&rdquo; She smiles.</p>

<p>Gong-gong is always dressed well: suede jackets, pressed wool, a sleek Kangol cap and shiny loafers. These days, he&rsquo;s still dapper but much less mobile. His walk is reduced to a shuffle.</p>

<p>He&rsquo;s shrunk over the years, but his charm is still there, shrouded by ailing health. As we leave, he grabs my arm and tells me he&rsquo;d like to attend my wedding soon and leaves me a kiss on the neck.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
