<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Regeneration | Finding Momentum]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/category/regeneration/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-25T11:44:37-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Hao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intern lessons learned]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/08/20/intern-lessons-learned/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-20T00:21:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/08/20/intern-lessons-learned</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Regeneration interns and I are wrapping up our year here at church. What have I learned?</p>

<h3>This was the year I stopped romanticizing urban ministry.</h3>

<p>I honestly came in with the idea that I was going to be really warmhearted and be an amazing rescuer and friend of the poor who could really see peoples' humanity past their issues. Instead, I found myself bitter at a lot of folks. R, who was doing great in his alcohol recovery, stole from us. We banned M from sleeping on our porch steps because her sharp urine scent was too much. P sleeps in the bushes, but occasionally defecates in the lot. I learned to dread the sound of the doorbell, which meant inconveniencing me to run up and answer the door and heat up some food. I hated being inconvenienced.</p>

<p>I learned that the poor despise the rich with the lens of entitlement, and the rich despise the poor with a lens of laziness and deservedness. I now see the complex web of power structures, decadeslong injustices, and people that give up in the face of overwhelming difficulty. I wrestle a lot with a desire to escape and turn my back. I hesitate to press in. I know now, ever more than ever, that we both need Jesus to humble us and equalize us.</p>

<h3>This was a year of community</h3>

<p>Take our recent baptism from a couple of months ago. R*, an African-American member who has wrestled with a long history of alcoholism and other issues, was prayed over by P, an older white man, S, a hapa young professional, and Betty, a wheelchair-bound white lady. I looked at the picture and wondered what can explain this except the Gospel?</p>

<p>Or the time that Eric engineered a sled so that we could take Betty, wheelchair and all, down to Ocean Beach for a bonfire. What can explain that?</p>

<p>Or the times that we hit up In-n-Out at random times in the middle of the night, or did a monthly San Tung run, or chowed on Yummy Guide after a Betty dropoff. I&rsquo;m going to remember running trails with Nate, or swimming with Eric and Justin. And there was that one time that Eric did my chores for me while I worked on some programming project because he saw I was stressed. &lt;3.</p>

<h3>This was a year of slowing down</h3>

<p>I realized that I live from task to task and thrive on stress. I need to stop this. I know this because I feel really antsy if I go the whole day without knocking anything out from my todo list. I will literally feel like exploding.</p>

<p>We live in a world of to-do lists and Getting Things Done. I am learning to stop, chat, laugh, and listen.</p>

<h3>This was a year of humility.</h3>

<p>I never liked doing my cleaning chores, or being asked to do something that was really inconvenient to my schedule. But those service times were pretty sweet if I had the right attitude. I will say that I got a lot of sermons knocked out while scrubbing toilets.</p>

<h3>This was a year of getting better at people things</h3>

<p>&hellip;and not be so clueless with friendships and relationships &lsquo;n stuff.</p>

<h3>This was a year of recentering</h3>

<p>And in the end, I want Jesus' reality more than ever. I&rsquo;m learning that God&rsquo;s a good dad, and I can trust him.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Today was a good day]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/07/03/today-was-a-good-day/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-03T00:11:10-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/07/03/today-was-a-good-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Channeling Ice Cube:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>94610 prayer walk with church community. Gary shared that doing these walks builds hope in us&hellip; helps us remember there&rsquo;s hope for Oakland. Give us eyes and ears and a heart for the city and our neighborhood. And afterwards I bought a brioche knot + a pizza slice at Arizmendi and 2 peaches from the farmer&rsquo;s market. Freakin good.</p></li>
<li><p>Did a 35-mile loop from Regen to Lake Chabot and back via Skyline with Eric and a friend. Nothing but godawful fatigue at the end. Came back and passed out for a good while.</p></li>
<li><p>Microwave TJ curry for dinner + a diet Coke someone left in the fridge. Amazing.</p></li>
<li><p>Sent Betty back with Kylan. Today I didn&rsquo;t mind.</p></li>
<li><p>Cleaned bathrooms and the kitchen, and enjoyed the alone time. Thought a lot about how I&rsquo;ve changed this year.</p></li>
<li><p>Sat out in the night air for a few minutes and just took it in.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>I don&rsquo;t know what it was about today but it just felt <em>good</em>. God&rsquo;s been good to me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On listening to Betty]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/06/10/on-listening-to-betty/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-10T20:41:03-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/06/10/on-listening-to-betty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5769226387/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5069/5769226387_4cd938676c.jpg" alt="Betty" /></a></p>

<p>The most difficult (and yet I suspect one of the most rewarding) part of this year&rsquo;s internship has been to simply sit with somebody and listen. Yes, it&rsquo;s been maddeningly difficult with Betty, the lady pictured above.</p>

<p>Ask anybody; I&rsquo;m a busy, hyper-scheduled guy. But to listen to someone is to really allow yourself to be inconvenienced. To let them stop you in the middle of a busy hall and hear them out, to let someone know that their ramblings about the most inane things really <em>matter</em> to you can really communicate care.</p>

<p>But how many people in our American culture really care to listen to one another? Or are we always running place to place, never stopping long enough to talk and hear each other out? Perhaps we&rsquo;re too busy shouting over each other.</p>

<p>More often than not, I&rsquo;m half-listening to Betty and half-plotting my escape from the conversation (she is masterful at grabbing for your ear and not letting go). But what if, as Carol Johnston once told us, we decided to listen, <em>really listen</em> with undivided attention, until the other person has nothing left to say?</p>

<p>Betty and I have this love-hate relationship. I think she fights with me more than any other person. &ldquo;I feel like you just want to dump me off at my place, like a piece of trash&rdquo; she snarled at me one week. I was so pissed. But it&rsquo;s true; when I talk to her I dream of not talking to her. I don&rsquo;t value her opinions like I would a friend&rsquo;s. (And she smells).</p>

<p>But I&rsquo;ve been challenged to listen to her and see past her toxicity and defenses. Love can cover a multitude of (my obnoxious) sins. I sat down with her one afternoon and did my best to hear her out for an hour. She was so pleasant that it scared me. People are saying that she&rsquo;s changing. Maybe it&rsquo;s because some people in my community are really making an effort to sit down with her, share a meal, give a ride, and lend an ear.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh yeah,]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/04/20/oh-yeah/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-20T11:36:09-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/04/20/oh-yeah</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here&rsquo;s a few fun pictures:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5588748575/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5061/5588748575_b432b58ba9.jpg" alt="Intern Photoshoot" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5589348424/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5229/5589348424_3fd96d271d.jpg" alt="Intern Photoshoot" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5588746865/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5051/5588746865_002b3ed953.jpg" alt="Intern Photoshoot" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About to board]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/04/20/about-to-board/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-20T11:32:45-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/04/20/about-to-board</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m sitting in the terminal at SFO and about to board and it&rsquo;s finally hitting me&mdash;here we go. A few of you may have gotten this, but here&rsquo;s a quick recap of what I&rsquo;m going to spend the next few weeks doing:</p>

<p><strong>I'm going to Cebu</strong></p>

<p><strong>
</strong></p>

<p><strong>What: </strong>Missions trip to the Philippines with Regeneration, my church in Oakland.</p>

<p><strong>When: </strong>April 20th to May 3rd, 2011</p>

<p><strong>Why: </strong>Learn from anti-trafficking organizations &amp; support the local Church body.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5548186559/in/photostream/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5186/5548186559_70e047238c_m.jpg" alt="5548186559_70e047238c_m.jpg" /></a> <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5548765972/in/photostream/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5026/5548765972_4491753766_m.jpg" alt="5548765972_4491753766_m.jpg" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/2011-Support-Letter-Booklet.pdf">Read my full support letter (PDF)</a>.</p>

<p><strong>I&rsquo;d love your help!</strong></p>

<p><strong>
</strong></p>

<p><strong>Prayerfully:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Unity within our intern group, the wisdom to know how to work through conflicts and disagreements, and the prayerful hearts needed to daily equip ourselves with the Gospel.</p></li>
<li><p>Humility to move in a cross-cultural context, laying down our assumptions and being open toseeing the Kingdom there.</p></li>
<li><p>Spiritual protection as we move into an unfamiliar spiritual landscape.</p></li>
<li><p>For the Kingdom to continue to move powerfully in dark places amidst poverty, spiritual strongholds and oppression.</p></li>
<li><p>Joy! That the church body there would ooze Gospel joy.</p></li>
<li><p>That the staff at the Red Window Project would be strengthened with supernatural rest, community, faith, hope, &amp; love.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Please keep up with our prayer requests and trip updates on our blog: <a href="http://interns.regenerationweb.com/">http://interns.regenerationweb.com</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
