<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Memories | Finding Momentum]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/category/memories/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-04T12:32:06-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Hao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On being wild]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/09/23/on-being-wild/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-23T18:17:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/09/23/on-being-wild</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I miss running barefoot &mdash; there was something about running with the spring in your step, pushing gingerly against the grass, feeling the strength of the stride move through your legs and through your toes that made you feel powerful, or free, or wild. When I first started early on, I always felt sore and achy at the bottom of my foot, like pinpricks lived there. We&rsquo;d joke that running the lake barefoot was safe&mdash;so long as you didn&rsquo;t step on the needles. A few times I felt a sharp pain and swore I did step on one&hellip; only to find out that I was fine. But as the calluses built, your stride adjusted and you would feel safer, and the stones wouldn&rsquo;t cut you anymore and you&rsquo;d run a little faster, leaning into the slicing chill, ignoring the numbness of running on wet grass on the north end of the lake and run home in darkness against the dotted glow of Lake Merritt&rsquo;s necklace.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve had the thought where I wished I could have been more wild when I was younger. Maybe it&rsquo;d be kind of cool to grow up and live in some remote town in the forest. I&rsquo;d like to run freely in the dirt and swim in a few lakes. I would have liked to learn how to wrestle and gotten in fights and build forts and bruise a few more knees and kiss a few more girls. I&rsquo;d like to have known the strength in my back and courage in my heart.  I remember always being fascinated with the protagonist in <em>My Side of the Mountain</em> &mdash; the idea of this boy living in the woods fending for himself, scavenging berries and tanning leather and hunting for venison (and tending to his own pet <em>falcon</em> &mdash; now that was frickin cool).</p>

<p>A memory circa 1998: my family is skiing at Yosemite and I&rsquo;m tired. I ask my Dad if I can go back by myself &mdash; the shuttle bus will be an hour ride down to the Valley floor. I must have been twelve, max. It is snowing heavily. He hands me the keys tells me to go ahead, and I make that ride back down myself. That day I feel like I&rsquo;ve crossed a threshold.</p>

<p>These days there are places in my life where I can say &mdash; I&rsquo;m going to be wild. <em>I&rsquo;m going to fight for this</em>, or <em>I&rsquo;m going to figure this out</em>. I&rsquo;m going to do this because as a grown man, I still want to run, and explore, and give it a good try.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gong gong & puo puo]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/01/23/gong-gong-puo-puo/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-23T10:04:35-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/01/23/gong-gong-puo-puo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My grandfather (ah gong, or 外公, but we call him gong gong), driven by winds of Communist change, arrived in Taiwan in the 1940s. He was a Fuzhou businessman, 26 at the time. He was a businessman, relatively wealthy and educated, and fled from the incoming Communists.</p>

<p>He met my grandmother (ah ma, or 外媽 &mdash; but we&rsquo;ve grown up calling her puo puo) while they both worked as schoolteachers at the same elementary school.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Your ah gong was a handsome man&rdquo; my grandmother says with a chuckle and a glimmer in her eye. She is dignified, ladylike, and precise. She bears eyes with depth, holding her teacup with deliberate old-world delicacy. My early memories are sprinkled with her constant presence in our house, making fantastic food and reading me chinese fables for bedtime stories.</p>

<p>They met in the years in between the world wars, when the world was changing. My grandma was native Taiwanese, telling me about the world she grew up in, hearing American bombers fly overhead, when alarms would sound and they would have to head to the mountains to hide in the hills. Taiwan was different then, they were raised to believe they were Japanese.</p>

<p>They fell in love, but they don&rsquo;t speak much about it nowadays. I wonder how it was back then. She was trained as a schoolteacher, and he must have been good with the kids given his gregarious charm. It&rsquo;s not hard to imagine why they fell in love, but how? I wonder if they can still remember.</p>

<p>These days, they live in Taipei in a modern apartment, paneled in marble and dark wood. His hands tremble when they reach for the dishes on the table. She reaches for the dish and steadies it for him. After each meal he silently shuffles to the couch and picks his teeth with a toothpick and looks out the window at the glassy beams of the Taipei 101 tower.</p>

<p>Her family would have nothing to do with him. He was an outsider, one of the KMT occupiers. Stories ran rampant about KMT men looking for Taiwanese wives while keeping a wife back in China. What did my great-grandfather think of him? Did they ever meet? Or did he forbid their love from the outside?</p>

<p>So they eloped.</p>

<p>Annie asks if puo-puo gets tired of cooking for us. My dad laughs. &ldquo;I bet she loves it that we&rsquo;re here. She loves to cook.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The spread is enormous. Taro fish ball soup, fresh steamed fish from the market, boiled chicken, dumplings, radish salad, an array of steamed vegetables and guavas and wax apples for dessert. We lay there after each meal, stunned and deliriously happy.</p>

<p>My mom would tell me about how in the years down the road after their marriage, gong-gong would eventually win over my grandmother&rsquo;s family with his kindness, generosity, and charm and twinkle in his eye. I wonder what it was like, a slow, gradual warming, a reconciliation that may have taken years to mend.</p>

<p>My uncle calls us when we&rsquo;re there, asking if they want to come with them on their upcoming vacation to Japan. Puo-puo hesitates, smiling a bit, thinking. When she is thinking, she knits her brow and blinks slowly. It&rsquo;s her reserved nature that defines her elegance, I decide. But she is like a wall, difficult to read. I want to ask her about her young love.</p>

<p>&ldquo;No,&rdquo; she finally says, &ldquo;I should stay here. It&rsquo;s cold in Japan. And I need to be with your dad.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Later as we sit around the living room sharing our hopes for the new year (my dad puts us through these things) gong-gong makes an innocent face and tells us that his hope is that &ldquo;your puo-puo should visit Japan and get out of the house and not have to take care of me.&rdquo; She smiles.</p>

<p>Gong-gong is always dressed well: suede jackets, pressed wool, a sleek Kangol cap and shiny loafers. These days, he&rsquo;s still dapper but much less mobile. His walk is reduced to a shuffle.</p>

<p>He&rsquo;s shrunk over the years, but his charm is still there, shrouded by ailing health. As we leave, he grabs my arm and tells me he&rsquo;d like to attend my wedding soon and leaves me a kiss on the neck.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the other side of autumn]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/10/11/on-the-other-side-of-autumn/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-11T01:20:49-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/10/11/on-the-other-side-of-autumn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/10/11/on-the-other-side-of-autumn/ecef685d4cdd46838de3ad8c6d25515c_7/"><img src="http://www.andrewhao.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/ecef685d4cdd46838de3ad8c6d25515c_7-500x500.jpg" alt="" /></a><a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/10/11/on-the-other-side-of-autumn/e68c24996c324dbdbe77a4f49f20ea60_7/"><img src="http://www.andrewhao.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/e68c24996c324dbdbe77a4f49f20ea60_7-500x500.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>I smelled it coming last week, but it didn&rsquo;t arrive until today. It smelled like autumn, it was warm rain, ticklish; it was musty with diamond dew and faded memories of running through these trees at our old church camp site, redwood trees tickling the clouds and the sweet fragrance of pine cones and the pricks of needles in my shoes. That&rsquo;s the kind of place where the mist envelops your eyes and causes you to blink, over and over and over again. Memories of the bell ringing on the steeple, calling us in for dinner as we would push past adults with understanding smiles to get to turkey and gravy and pumpkin pie, stuffing ourselves and running back out into the wild, pretending we were secret agents.</p>

<p>But there it was again in a different form, carrying us back from LA through the fertile fields of the Central Valley, sunlight streaking over our heads and we drove back and debated whether we were old or not. That previous night at the wedding I asked my table if they&rsquo;d ever really felt <em>old</em>, and that maybe the better question was whether we ever wished we were <em>young</em> again. We all laughed it off, or at least a bit nervously. I wonder if there&rsquo;s a slight terror to the feeling of it overcoming us, afraid that maybe one day we&rsquo;d wake up and feel some gloom of extra gravity and it&rsquo;d hit us: <em>oh crap </em>and we&rsquo;d carry this fear to our twenty-fifth year high school reunions, strung &lsquo;round our necks like medallions. But there rushing past sunkissed fields listening to country crooners I wondered if I&rsquo;d ever really grow old, with the sun on my back and laughter, sweet laughter around me.</p>

<p>I think the warmth of autumn reminds me that all things must change, they must grow and move in season. One day I know I must be old, and I will have known a love that is young and weathered, resilient and yielding and tested True. I will have known the courage of a little boy, spoken to the weighty fears of my young man self, into the maturity that awaits on the other side, the line that we will not know we have crossed until the leaves have long since changed their color.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dreams of a city of ash]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/04/15/dreams-of-a-city-of-ash/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-15T11:04:30-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/04/15/dreams-of-a-city-of-ash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/1756742112/"><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2379/1756742112_a54cf5e9a8.jpg" alt="Sensations - Awaken the Dawn" /></a></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s like the evenings I spent in Central Asia years ago, sprawled on a stiff hotel bed and journaling until darkness fell. In my headphones the refrain would play: <em>in your presence, all fear is gone, in your presence&hellip;</em> And it&rsquo;s all I could cling to, because that month-or-so in that land was one of the loneliest I&rsquo;ve had.</p>

<p>That first week, as I was climbing onto the bus, a trio of teenage boys rushed off and shoved me to the side as they exited, so close you could feel the heat radiating off their brows. I thought them rude, but then caught myself and reminded myself that they&rsquo;re just boys. The thought lasted about two seconds; that was the first time I had my wallet stolen.</p>

<p>I still think about the feeling of Sosho and I crammed in the back of the bus, clutching our bags tight (myself, in particular), watching the spires of mosques pass by and watching Muslims pray on the sidewalks during afternoon prayers, their foreheads pressed into the concrete and lips moving in fervent prayer. I remember seeing a diseased boy, his arms both amputated and his face marked with sweat and soot, pleading with his eyes for his throat was parched. Our Muslim friends were generous: they gave alms to the poor, they believed Allah would reward them for their generosity.</p>

<p>The city is one of the most polluted cities in the world; it lies in a dry valley and is reputed as the most landlocked city in the world. Soot and ash from surrounding factories linger over us in a haze. Day by day, thousands of new immigrants arrive by train. The city is exploding; everybody is covered in soot; it is hot; tempers flare, a bus tire explodes and the people begrudgingly walk off the bus and wait for another to come along.</p>

<p>I also remember wandering the parks of that city, and watching the people mill about, their faces blank (as strangers generally are to other strangers), and trying to think about God but constantly being interrupted by the heat and smog, thoughts flitting back and forth from prayer to a red bean popsicle (glory!).</p>

<p>We would hear stories of busloads of South Korean tourists who would come into the city. One of the missionaries told us that they were actually followers of the Way, who would circle the great square in the center of the city and blanket it with prayers. She knew because she would see them walk about, their mouths moving inaudibly and their eyes locked onto the heart of the city and its people. She would see them and her heart would explode and she told us that she would want to shout <em>we&rsquo;re here! we follow the Way too!</em></p>

<p>The weather here is impetuous; one day it&rsquo;ll be 80 degrees and in the evening it&rsquo;ll be below freezing and snowing. It&rsquo;s much like the food, bursting with spices and seasonings and cooled with a dollop of frosty yogurt. The food, oh, I still do dream about it, the <em>lagman</em> and lamb kebabs, the feeling of growing dizzier with the sights and smells of the food stalls at the bazaars.</p>

<p>I wasn&rsquo;t very spiritually-minded on that trip, and I felt that God knew it was okay. I couldn&rsquo;t shake my homesickness on days when I&rsquo;d want to run from the oppressive heat, when the blathering of denizens would take its toll on my patience, and my stomach would rebel at the stream of foreign food I kept trying to feed it with. But still, there was that feeling&mdash;&ndash;</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s like the mornings I&rsquo;d take a jog out onto the deserted streets, watching the sun rise and hearing the burst of an oven igniting, the flapping of pigeon wings, the distant car horn and the slight hum of towering cranes, unofficial city guardians. And though I couldn&rsquo;t shake the homesickness, I knew I was in God&rsquo;s presence. Even today, I look back and know I was with the one they call Allah. I&rsquo;d have these visions of his grace gathering in storm clouds and falling like rain, clearing the air, turning streets into creeks and sprouting trees on their banks.</p>

<p>Soon the ash would fill my lungs and force me, coughing, to turn around and crawl back into bed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Staying close to the ground]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/03/23/staying-close-to-the-ground/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-23T01:43:07-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/03/23/staying-close-to-the-ground</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.andrewhao.com/?attachment_id=1416"><img src="http://www.andrewhao.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/1300076147-500x500.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>A few cloudy Sundays ago I was watching Bruce play with Darren on the steps of our church. Screaming fire trucks were storming our street. Bruce ran down the steps, swept a wide-eyed Darren into his arms and ran down to watch the commotion fade down East 15th.</p>

<p>Darren&rsquo;s eyes were bright and mouth was agape. &ldquo;That was a fire twuck!&rdquo; he exclaimed, jabbing a stubby finger in the direction of the receding lights.</p>

<p>Man, Darren was so taken by that truck.</p>

<p>&mdash;</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been thinking lately about how simple we need to become to &ldquo;get&rdquo; to the Father heart of God. I&rsquo;m really tired of overthinking things. I&rsquo;m tired of trying to push things on my own or intellectualizing you or my purpose here.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m thinking about this Imposter that I&rsquo;ve created, the image in me that I like to put forth as someone competent, artsy, smart, funny, mature. My greatest fear is that someone will discover me in the times when I can&rsquo;t keep up the ruse and find me unlovable. My Imposter can cover that for me, so I don&rsquo;t have to face the disappointment of being myself.</p>

<ol type="a">
<li></li>
</ol>


<p>I am surrounded by my friends, but this memory is unattached with context. I don&rsquo;t know where this is or how old I am (how old am I? sixteen?) But there is laughter: pale white walls of laughter, ringing in my ears. They are laughing at me (with me? something I said?) and I&rsquo;ve got this stupid smile on my face and I don&rsquo;t get it. All I can do is play along and smile, imagining they&rsquo;re not laughing at me, they&rsquo;re laughing because I&rsquo;m self-deprecating and I&rsquo;m funny and my cheeks burn, straining under the weight of this two-ton grin. Surely they see it&rsquo;s not real, but I hope against hope that nobody notices.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>I am six, buried in numbers, two by two by six by twelve by what the hell is happening. There is a wall of numbers rushing straight at me, and I can&rsquo;t think through the tears but all I know how to do is swim to the other side of the numbers. If I can trust my slipping memory, the numbers will fall out before the seconds expire and the waters won&rsquo;t overwhelm me but alas, the waves are lapping over the edge and my eyes begin to overflow.</p>

<p>III.</p>

<p>A memory of performing, being on stage, drinking the laughter or applause or accolades of friends. I love it here. I feel at home here. I feel powerful here. But the lights turn off and people go home to their families and I am left sitting in my car with the key in the ignition, soon to be turned if not for the weight of an inconsolable loneliness. What do you do when you pour yourself out yet you cannot drink your fill?</p>

<p>&mdash;</p>

<p>Jesus, I just want to hang out with you and have you sweep me into your arms and we can run after fire trucks. Or we can do what you wanna do. I don&rsquo;t care. I just wanna be the kid with a stupid grin on his face watching his Dad do his thing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
