<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Words | Finding Momentum]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/category/words/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-04T12:32:06-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Hao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A brother, a daughter]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2013/01/18/a-brother-a-daughter/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-18T20:56:43-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2013/01/18/a-brother-a-daughter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mike calls me out of the blue.</p>

<p>I pick up the receiver to a sonic wave of grief. They shot my baby, he wails, they took my girl.</p>

<p>You loved her a lot, I offer, the words stumbling out of my mouth.</p>

<p>I loved her like my own.</p>

<p>Her daddy passed away in November. Harry. He helped me move into my apartment, put in the down payment&hellip; now he&rsquo;s gone.</p>

<p>Wailing, the sobs come in waves. Bubbling, snorting, sniffling. Mike is a mess.</p>

<p>Listen.</p>

<p>I took Jubrille shopping just last week to get boots. Right out here &mdash; that Skechers on Bancroft? Giovana didn&rsquo;t like this one pair that Jubrille really liked oh God oh god oh gawd oh god</p>

<p>Silence from time to time&hellip; hello? Silence. Hello?</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still here.</p>

<p>She was the last of 2012&hellip; I wish I was the last of 2012. I&rsquo;m done, Drew, I&rsquo;m done. It hurts so bad. Why&rsquo;d they take my baby?</p>

<p>How&rsquo;s Belinda?</p>

<p>The sobbing continues. She&rsquo;s&hellip; bad, Drew. Belinda&rsquo;s doing bad. You gotta call her man.</p>

<p>Jabrille, Gabriel, Jabrille, Gabriel &mdash; like the angel. Here&rsquo;s her picture.</p>

<p>Mike shows a video to me from his phone, taking his time to swipe through about twenty different pictures. There the image is, her room, shadowy in the afternoon, the sun filtering through dark curtains. Graduation photos, bags from various stores taped to the walls &mdash; FOOT LOCKER, FOREVER 21, H&amp;M. There is the sound of Mike choking back tears. There is a man in the room too, his arms slouched over his knees, giving Mike &amp; camera a long look.</p>

<p>Be strong Mike for my mom and my sister. Pull yourself together. You can&rsquo;t cry.</p>

<p>Giovana is shut off. Won&rsquo;t talk. Can&rsquo;t blame her. Her dad just passed too. And now her sister&hellip;</p>

<p><em>At the farewell funeral I met Giovana, who looked a lot skinnier and wider-eyed than I had imagined her being. She was only a year older than her sister, and walked shyly around the mourners, talking in side glances with her high school friends who looked pained and out of place. Some of them were smiling &mdash; whether it was the incongruity of it all, or using humor to mask deep sadness, I didn&rsquo;t know.</em></p>

<p>The candlelight vigil was last week, but oh man. It&rsquo;s gonna rain, Mike says, I gotta get there and get the teddy bears in her room.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m feeling out of place. The Kingpin owner comes over to our table. Mike says: you hear the news. They took my daughter. Shot over New Years. The shop owner comes over and clutches Mike&rsquo;s phone loosely. Yeah. He looks concerned, then hands the phone back to Mike.</p>

<p>Everywhere I go I see girls that look like Jabrille. I stop and look at them. The other week we came out here and she bought boots at Skechers here. Right here in Berkeley.</p>

<p>Belinda says now you gotta help me raise the girls. So I say to Giovana: first thing is you can&rsquo;t go outside. Don&rsquo;t hang out with your hoochie mama friends. And she didn&rsquo;t say nothing.</p>

<p>Over our table now Mike slides over to me an open newspaper, the SF Chronicle, opened to an article about Malala, Pakistani girl who got shot by the Taliban. Read this? he asks. So sad.</p>

<p>You gotta be strong, Mike. Wait till this all blows over. I gotta be strong. I gotta be strong for Belinda.</p>

<p><em>Jubrille&rsquo;s viewing was the first viewing I&rsquo;ve ever been at, and she looked&hellip; unnatural. Plastic. There used to be a soul in there. Mike would stand over the casket and kissed her on the forehead. Justin and I stood awkwardly and waited in line and paid our respects and then, feeling a bit of displacement, we sat down in the pews and let Mike sit behind us and rattle on about his plans for the obituary. The entire scene felt unreal. Children running around, crawling under the pews, laughing. Belinda, who I finally met, was nicely put together, chatting it up with loved ones. I&rsquo;d overdressed; I had thought to dress up, but felt self-conscious in my tie and nice shoes. Walking back to the van Justin remarked to me and nobody in particular, is it not crazy that this kind of thing happens in Oakland twice a week?</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Push & pull II]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/10/03/push-pull-ii/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-03T23:01:21-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/10/03/push-pull-ii</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oakland, tonight I swam in your streets and felt the cool of your night. I think to myself how I feel strong when the pull stroke feels easy, and think to memorize the tones of the sky at dusk when I pull to the side for air &mdash; half the sky a fading incandescent red, the other a fluorescent blue. I find, for a few moments of grace that people shimmer with a quiet mystery when they&rsquo;re underwater, the light from the pool lamps refracting, flexing, arcing over their bodies. To you, Oakland, I feel a sense of sheepishness, I</p>

<p>confess it&rsquo;s taken me years to learn to love you and I realize it&rsquo;s because I&rsquo;m still guarded when I&rsquo;m around you. It&rsquo;s taken time to understand why the bus lady sings bluesfully to herself at the stop. She does not want your change, but she wants you to recognize her and see her, approach her and hold her. You too have a dual personality, you like your sister are hot and cold. Your people struggle up against each other and quarrel, I remember how Pancho would come back to our steps every night after we told him to leave&mdash;no disrespect, he insisted&mdash;but we&rsquo;d start up all over on the same note. You&rsquo;re my partna right? Right, I&rsquo;d say, knowing it to be the feeblest lie, and wondering if he was being facetious or if I was the most cynical man on earth. You&rsquo;re my partna. Push and pull, push and pull. Oakland, I realize I still don&rsquo;t</p>

<p>get you but I can&rsquo;t let that get me down, because I still sense the electric buzz in your veins, and I have that freeze frame photo of the shimmer during that swim. I still have the sensation of lingering night warmth from the soil after a hot day and the small-sensation I get standing under the expanse of your patchquilt sky.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Push & pull I]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/10/03/push-and-pull-i/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-03T22:57:35-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/10/03/push-and-pull-i</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>San Francisco wraps me up with hot pumice breath and does not let go. She follows me with a sincerity that I cannot shake, offering the fruits of her cacophony as the throaty rumbling of cable cars, as the muted quarreling of European travelers, blue eyed children in tow, as azalea sunbursts lining the steps I jog each afternoon. She orchestrates the movements of ten thousand bicyclists. She punctuates the skies with glass ornaments and fighter-jet jewels. and lures in her prey with the offerings of raven gold parlayed over her streets. She charms me over then just as quickly, she turns</p>

<p>cold; suddenly I am colored frigid by blasts of air conditioning from cavernous parking garages, blown to and fro through alleyways. Her eyes darken by murky sea gales, and nighttime cools her zeal.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On being wild]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/09/23/on-being-wild/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-23T18:17:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/09/23/on-being-wild</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I miss running barefoot &mdash; there was something about running with the spring in your step, pushing gingerly against the grass, feeling the strength of the stride move through your legs and through your toes that made you feel powerful, or free, or wild. When I first started early on, I always felt sore and achy at the bottom of my foot, like pinpricks lived there. We&rsquo;d joke that running the lake barefoot was safe&mdash;so long as you didn&rsquo;t step on the needles. A few times I felt a sharp pain and swore I did step on one&hellip; only to find out that I was fine. But as the calluses built, your stride adjusted and you would feel safer, and the stones wouldn&rsquo;t cut you anymore and you&rsquo;d run a little faster, leaning into the slicing chill, ignoring the numbness of running on wet grass on the north end of the lake and run home in darkness against the dotted glow of Lake Merritt&rsquo;s necklace.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve had the thought where I wished I could have been more wild when I was younger. Maybe it&rsquo;d be kind of cool to grow up and live in some remote town in the forest. I&rsquo;d like to run freely in the dirt and swim in a few lakes. I would have liked to learn how to wrestle and gotten in fights and build forts and bruise a few more knees and kiss a few more girls. I&rsquo;d like to have known the strength in my back and courage in my heart.  I remember always being fascinated with the protagonist in <em>My Side of the Mountain</em> &mdash; the idea of this boy living in the woods fending for himself, scavenging berries and tanning leather and hunting for venison (and tending to his own pet <em>falcon</em> &mdash; now that was frickin cool).</p>

<p>A memory circa 1998: my family is skiing at Yosemite and I&rsquo;m tired. I ask my Dad if I can go back by myself &mdash; the shuttle bus will be an hour ride down to the Valley floor. I must have been twelve, max. It is snowing heavily. He hands me the keys tells me to go ahead, and I make that ride back down myself. That day I feel like I&rsquo;ve crossed a threshold.</p>

<p>These days there are places in my life where I can say &mdash; I&rsquo;m going to be wild. <em>I&rsquo;m going to fight for this</em>, or <em>I&rsquo;m going to figure this out</em>. I&rsquo;m going to do this because as a grown man, I still want to run, and explore, and give it a good try.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the first run]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/06/05/on-the-first-run/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-05T09:50:37-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/06/05/on-the-first-run</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>I can run!</em> I&rsquo;m on a jog on my lunch break for the first time in four months, and I want to tell it to everyone: tourists with itchy, sunstroked faces crowding Chinatown, Dan, down-cast on the street corner in front of that handmade sushi roll place, forty-something yuppies with yoga mats yelping as I dodge them by. I&rsquo;m drinking it in, the clangs of cable-car bells, the way they fade off when the car heads up the hill on California, the way the riders have a faraway look as if they&rsquo;ve seen something familiar yet mysterious (maybe it&rsquo;s warm nostalgia for things they can&rsquo;t remember).</p>

<p>Everything is beautiful: the way the buttery spires on Saints Peter &amp; Paul church melt into the sky. The easy spring in my stride, which surprises me. The pleasant shade of laurel trees on Jackson, set against Telegraph Hill. I have to hold myself back from racing other runners down the Embarcadero because I&rsquo;m liable to hurt myself again. But I race them anyways. <em>I can run! </em>I sing a song in my head; it is a simple one for which I&rsquo;ve forgotten the verse but not the refrain: <em>he who began a good work in you / will be faithful to complete it</em>. And so it goes.</p>

<p>Four miles in, I lope to the center of the divide in front of the Ferry Building and stretch below the sculpture in its center, noticing a small twinge in my heel. Easy now, I tell myself. Don&rsquo;t let it get to your head. But the endorphins take over and I feel light again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
