<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hiking | Finding Momentum]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/category/hiking/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-22T18:11:25-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Hao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new way to move]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2014/10/01/a-way-to-move/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-01T21:25:42-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2014/10/01/a-way-to-move</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh my God, I&rsquo;m cold. I guess I didn&rsquo;t imagine this on my retreat.
30MPH gusts blowing at me, stinging my face with snow bits. Nature is beautiful yet harsh, and I
realize that the City Boy in me is not quite cut out for this. We aren&rsquo;t
in Oakland any more.</p>

<p>Nobody is on this snow-covered trail. I am following moose tracks some ways in the
distance. I imagine it ambling toward me, at some earlier point in the
morning. Is it a moose? Or a horse? Paw prints emerge in the snow a bit
further on, and I wonder if there are mountain lions nearby.</p>

<p>That morning I drove up to Lake Brainard and was met with blasting winds
coming over the mountain pass. I changed my mind, <em>screw this</em>, and I
jumped back into the car and drove a few miles down the road, figuring
that I&rsquo;d take a couple of miles of hiking in the forest to warm up before navigating through the lower lake.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/15438591602"><img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5601/15438591602_eb9f37844c_b.jpg" alt="Lake Isabelle" /></a></p>

<p>Three hours and a mere six miles later, I&rsquo;m at
Lake Isabelle, a frosty, glassy-blued alpine lake, and the sun has just
begun to warm me. Alas, the gusts are still there. I see two men make
their way up on the trail pass above, their voices echoing off the
mountain walls. The snow somehow makes their voices travel further, or
I&rsquo;m really desperate for human contact.</p>

<p>I think of all the hikes I&rsquo;ve taken with friends in the past and for a
moment, desperately wish they were here, just so I could stop feeling so
lonely, or to have some conversation to keep my mind turning.</p>

<p>Annie asked me the other day
what I think about when I&rsquo;m running. Sometimes I&rsquo;m singing a song in my
head, or other times I&rsquo;m just picturing me entering the next trail. At
the moment, I&rsquo;m envisioning how warm the car is and how good the bed is
going to feel. I&rsquo;ve been turning over a phrase in my head for the past
couple of days: &ldquo;A new way to be human.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s a line from a Switchfoot
song, and I have a suspicion that it has some significance for me here.</p>

<p>I meet more
backpackers coming back the other way: <em>High winds, no visibility, we&rsquo;re
turning around</em>. I make mental notes to go as far as I can, and realize
that honestly, I have no idea how I will know. Is it fear? Is it
physical tiredness?</p>

<p>In the end, I turn around because I&rsquo;m cold.</p>

<p>The clouds are getting
darker and the gusts are biting more fiercely. I arrive at a snowy field at 12000 feet and look up. The
next climb is totally shrouded in a dark cloud. Two men are hurriedly
making their way down from the top. I shiver. Let&rsquo;s go home.</p>

<p>This solo retreat is exactly rooting
out the things I want and love. I desire the warmth of friendship, the
experience of beauty, the purpose of a journey. I did come here to be
alone, but I did also come here to find a new way to move and be human.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
