<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Internship | Finding Momentum]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/category/internship/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-19T19:54:05-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Hao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intern lessons learned]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/08/20/intern-lessons-learned/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-20T00:21:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/08/20/intern-lessons-learned</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Regeneration interns and I are wrapping up our year here at church. What have I learned?</p>

<h3>This was the year I stopped romanticizing urban ministry.</h3>

<p>I honestly came in with the idea that I was going to be really warmhearted and be an amazing rescuer and friend of the poor who could really see peoples' humanity past their issues. Instead, I found myself bitter at a lot of folks. R, who was doing great in his alcohol recovery, stole from us. We banned M from sleeping on our porch steps because her sharp urine scent was too much. P sleeps in the bushes, but occasionally defecates in the lot. I learned to dread the sound of the doorbell, which meant inconveniencing me to run up and answer the door and heat up some food. I hated being inconvenienced.</p>

<p>I learned that the poor despise the rich with the lens of entitlement, and the rich despise the poor with a lens of laziness and deservedness. I now see the complex web of power structures, decadeslong injustices, and people that give up in the face of overwhelming difficulty. I wrestle a lot with a desire to escape and turn my back. I hesitate to press in. I know now, ever more than ever, that we both need Jesus to humble us and equalize us.</p>

<h3>This was a year of community</h3>

<p>Take our recent baptism from a couple of months ago. R*, an African-American member who has wrestled with a long history of alcoholism and other issues, was prayed over by P, an older white man, S, a hapa young professional, and Betty, a wheelchair-bound white lady. I looked at the picture and wondered what can explain this except the Gospel?</p>

<p>Or the time that Eric engineered a sled so that we could take Betty, wheelchair and all, down to Ocean Beach for a bonfire. What can explain that?</p>

<p>Or the times that we hit up In-n-Out at random times in the middle of the night, or did a monthly San Tung run, or chowed on Yummy Guide after a Betty dropoff. I&rsquo;m going to remember running trails with Nate, or swimming with Eric and Justin. And there was that one time that Eric did my chores for me while I worked on some programming project because he saw I was stressed. &lt;3.</p>

<h3>This was a year of slowing down</h3>

<p>I realized that I live from task to task and thrive on stress. I need to stop this. I know this because I feel really antsy if I go the whole day without knocking anything out from my todo list. I will literally feel like exploding.</p>

<p>We live in a world of to-do lists and Getting Things Done. I am learning to stop, chat, laugh, and listen.</p>

<h3>This was a year of humility.</h3>

<p>I never liked doing my cleaning chores, or being asked to do something that was really inconvenient to my schedule. But those service times were pretty sweet if I had the right attitude. I will say that I got a lot of sermons knocked out while scrubbing toilets.</p>

<h3>This was a year of getting better at people things</h3>

<p>&hellip;and not be so clueless with friendships and relationships &lsquo;n stuff.</p>

<h3>This was a year of recentering</h3>

<p>And in the end, I want Jesus' reality more than ever. I&rsquo;m learning that God&rsquo;s a good dad, and I can trust him.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bits and pieces of orphaned conversations]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/08/18/bits-and-pieces-of-orphaned-conversations/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-18T23:56:13-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/08/18/bits-and-pieces-of-orphaned-conversations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My nephew, he&rsquo;s the one in Afghanistan. Sometimes I wish I could take his place because if I go&hellip; <em>(silence)</em> it doesn&rsquo;t matter.</p>

<p>Listen, I ain&rsquo;t gonna lie about it. I&rsquo;m an alcoholic. I don&rsquo;t drink because I&rsquo;m sad. I drink because I liiiiiiike drinking.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t know if I can trust you anymore, man. You lost my trust.</p>

<p>Hey, can I get a flashlight? There&rsquo;s someone behind these bushes.</p>

<p>You got a bite to eat? Listen man I just need a bite. Did I come too late? What time is it?</p>

<p>I been all around Oakland, and this is the safest place to be.</p>

<p>Get out. You can&rsquo;t just come in here and help yourself to our food.</p>

<p>Is she breathing? Yes? Okay let me call the ambulance.</p>

<p>Listen man, I feel hurt I don&rsquo;t know <em>who&rsquo;s</em> making those accusations about me but I&rsquo;m telling you I ain&rsquo;t selling the food. It hurts me that they&rsquo;re saying these things.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s Essie&rsquo;s birthday today! <em>(singing of birthday songs).</em></p>

<p>I told you not to sleep on these steps but I saw you here last night.</p>

<p>Me and her are gonna get married on the 14th.</p>

<p>Rico thinks he&rsquo;s gonna die. I think he&rsquo;s given up.</p>

<p>Rico&rsquo;s been doing real well lately. I think he&rsquo;s turning a corner.</p>

<p>Listen man can I say a prayer for us?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Today was a good day]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/07/03/today-was-a-good-day/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-03T00:11:10-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/07/03/today-was-a-good-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Channeling Ice Cube:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>94610 prayer walk with church community. Gary shared that doing these walks builds hope in us&hellip; helps us remember there&rsquo;s hope for Oakland. Give us eyes and ears and a heart for the city and our neighborhood. And afterwards I bought a brioche knot + a pizza slice at Arizmendi and 2 peaches from the farmer&rsquo;s market. Freakin good.</p></li>
<li><p>Did a 35-mile loop from Regen to Lake Chabot and back via Skyline with Eric and a friend. Nothing but godawful fatigue at the end. Came back and passed out for a good while.</p></li>
<li><p>Microwave TJ curry for dinner + a diet Coke someone left in the fridge. Amazing.</p></li>
<li><p>Sent Betty back with Kylan. Today I didn&rsquo;t mind.</p></li>
<li><p>Cleaned bathrooms and the kitchen, and enjoyed the alone time. Thought a lot about how I&rsquo;ve changed this year.</p></li>
<li><p>Sat out in the night air for a few minutes and just took it in.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>I don&rsquo;t know what it was about today but it just felt <em>good</em>. God&rsquo;s been good to me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On listening to Betty]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/06/10/on-listening-to-betty/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-10T20:41:03-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/06/10/on-listening-to-betty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/5769226387/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5069/5769226387_4cd938676c.jpg" alt="Betty" /></a></p>

<p>The most difficult (and yet I suspect one of the most rewarding) part of this year&rsquo;s internship has been to simply sit with somebody and listen. Yes, it&rsquo;s been maddeningly difficult with Betty, the lady pictured above.</p>

<p>Ask anybody; I&rsquo;m a busy, hyper-scheduled guy. But to listen to someone is to really allow yourself to be inconvenienced. To let them stop you in the middle of a busy hall and hear them out, to let someone know that their ramblings about the most inane things really <em>matter</em> to you can really communicate care.</p>

<p>But how many people in our American culture really care to listen to one another? Or are we always running place to place, never stopping long enough to talk and hear each other out? Perhaps we&rsquo;re too busy shouting over each other.</p>

<p>More often than not, I&rsquo;m half-listening to Betty and half-plotting my escape from the conversation (she is masterful at grabbing for your ear and not letting go). But what if, as Carol Johnston once told us, we decided to listen, <em>really listen</em> with undivided attention, until the other person has nothing left to say?</p>

<p>Betty and I have this love-hate relationship. I think she fights with me more than any other person. &ldquo;I feel like you just want to dump me off at my place, like a piece of trash&rdquo; she snarled at me one week. I was so pissed. But it&rsquo;s true; when I talk to her I dream of not talking to her. I don&rsquo;t value her opinions like I would a friend&rsquo;s. (And she smells).</p>

<p>But I&rsquo;ve been challenged to listen to her and see past her toxicity and defenses. Love can cover a multitude of (my obnoxious) sins. I sat down with her one afternoon and did my best to hear her out for an hour. She was so pleasant that it scared me. People are saying that she&rsquo;s changing. Maybe it&rsquo;s because some people in my community are really making an effort to sit down with her, share a meal, give a ride, and lend an ear.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell me what you want, and I'll give you my name]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/05/02/tell-me-what-you-want-and-ill-give-you-my-name/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-02T18:23:08-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2011/05/02/tell-me-what-you-want-and-ill-give-you-my-name</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>you have come to us in royal fashion, your slippers triumphantly slapping against gravel, your elegant fingers drumming against our windowpanes. you keep up a good pace, sir. you glide alongside our car and smile your patented, ringmaster smile. we watch you through one-way tinted glass and air-conditioned cabins. you are a curious specimen, a caged animal proudly loping the length of your alley.</p>

<p>at this point you would expect us to roll down our windows and expose our foreign skin, salivating mouths and lusting faces. you have girls for us, young ones whose virginities and sexual prowess you tout loudly, in broken phrases and sentences.</p>

<p>you know us; men who come through for innocent interludes and escapades. we want to feel flesh against ours and imagine the whispers of past loves. others will inhale deeply of the choking, snarling scent of lust, leaving inkdrops suspended in an ever-darkening pool of water.</p>

<p>you know how desperately we prefer to believe that these girls want us. we operate in fantasies. you provide them for us; you are the sultan of sex and the purveyor of pleasure. you feel powerful: the kick you get in offering the services of your women is unmatched by the wide-eyed grins of your customers. men now boys, they are pressing their faces against glass, drooling over shiny toys in storefront windows.</p>

<p>doggedly you chase after cars. or they run after you. your fingernails clack against the windowpanes and offer what you know your customers want, even if they don&rsquo;t willingly realize it yet. you need us. you love us. you resent us.</p>

<p>you resent us because we come from outside and we take your women. you&rsquo;ve seen how we use them like cheap change. but you too have participated.</p>

<p>you are not yourself. you grew up in a rusting city, its long, rambling corridors locking you in to your quarter-peso life. your life has never been easy. this is the only way you know how to survive in this rotting place. you know it too, but to see your girls as human is exquisitely painful. they hold a mirror to you and at the corners you can make out the crumbling images of your sister and your mother.</p>

<p>you pretend not to notice how the girls thicken after each session. quickly they become armored fortresses, silk buttresses over bronzed skin. it is too humid here; you cannot keep the patina from running down their shoulders.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
