<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Andrew 2.0 | Finding Momentum]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/category/andrew-2-dot-0/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-18T19:13:26-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Hao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On changing, moving, and finding momentum]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2013/12/28/on-changing-moving-and-finding-momentum/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-28T13:59:08-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2013/12/28/on-changing-moving-and-finding-momentum</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To be honest? This year felt a little like autopilot. Like I was caught
dealing with <em>Life</em> as it happened, doing a zillion different things
(like I always do) and realizing that I needed to catch up with the
changes. At times, this year felt like waiting for things to happen to me.
Does that make sense?</p>

<p>Life is all about changes. Friends move away, jobs change, roles morph, and I found
myself wondering on more than one occasion &mdash; what&rsquo;s going on here?</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m feeling like I&rsquo;m being constantly faced with the struggle &mdash; how can
I change? How can I grow? Where it feels like sometimes my friends are
moving forward with their lives, there was a bit of soul-searching to be
done this year &mdash; what am I doing nowadays? Is there something I need to
be doing to grow and move forward?</p>

<p>Not much has changed in my life in the outside this year. I still work
at the same place. I&rsquo;m in the same community, and my friends are still
the same. Things are pretty good, and pretty stable.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m a creature of habit, and it takes a lot of external forces to make
me move. I don&rsquo;t like to travel (too much), preferring a trail run or a
good read or some heads-down coding time. I&rsquo;m a homebody, and I&rsquo;d much
rather spend my vacation time just relaxing at a nearby cafe. I&rsquo;ve eaten
oatmeal for breakfast, coffee in the morning, and lentils for dinner
wayyy too many times to count, (and gotten a lot of grief for it :) ).</p>

<p>But when do these habits start getting in the way of growth, or others'
growth? I&rsquo;ve learned that I have much to grow in my leadership. My
tendency is to focus way too much on the detail and not enough in the
strategy and vision. If you&rsquo;ve asked me what I was going to do two years
in the future, I&rsquo;d honestly have trouble telling you what that would be.</p>

<p>I wrestle with delegation, and sometimes I find myself in roles that
aren&rsquo;t fit for me anymore and not quite keeping up with my own growth.</p>

<p>So one of my hopes in my growth this year is to acknowledge change and
embrace transition and, hell, maybe even lean into some changes of my
own. At time of writing, I have no idea what that may mean, but the
thought is exciting and unappetizing and terrifying and that in itself
is probably a sign that that is What I Might Need. Maybe I need to go on
vacation more. Delegate more aggressively. Keep ruminating on long-term
dreams. Stuff like that. Yeah.</p>

<p>Maybe that&rsquo;s why I named this blog &ldquo;Finding Momentum&rdquo; so many years
ago &mdash; to crystallize a deep want to grow, adapt, and mature.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A brother, a daughter]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2013/01/18/a-brother-a-daughter/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-18T20:56:43-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2013/01/18/a-brother-a-daughter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mike calls me out of the blue.</p>

<p>I pick up the receiver to a sonic wave of grief. They shot my baby, he wails, they took my girl.</p>

<p>You loved her a lot, I offer, the words stumbling out of my mouth.</p>

<p>I loved her like my own.</p>

<p>Her daddy passed away in November. Harry. He helped me move into my apartment, put in the down payment&hellip; now he&rsquo;s gone.</p>

<p>Wailing, the sobs come in waves. Bubbling, snorting, sniffling. Mike is a mess.</p>

<p>Listen.</p>

<p>I took Jubrille shopping just last week to get boots. Right out here &mdash; that Skechers on Bancroft? Giovana didn&rsquo;t like this one pair that Jubrille really liked oh God oh god oh gawd oh god</p>

<p>Silence from time to time&hellip; hello? Silence. Hello?</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still here.</p>

<p>She was the last of 2012&hellip; I wish I was the last of 2012. I&rsquo;m done, Drew, I&rsquo;m done. It hurts so bad. Why&rsquo;d they take my baby?</p>

<p>How&rsquo;s Belinda?</p>

<p>The sobbing continues. She&rsquo;s&hellip; bad, Drew. Belinda&rsquo;s doing bad. You gotta call her man.</p>

<p>Jabrille, Gabriel, Jabrille, Gabriel &mdash; like the angel. Here&rsquo;s her picture.</p>

<p>Mike shows a video to me from his phone, taking his time to swipe through about twenty different pictures. There the image is, her room, shadowy in the afternoon, the sun filtering through dark curtains. Graduation photos, bags from various stores taped to the walls &mdash; FOOT LOCKER, FOREVER 21, H&amp;M. There is the sound of Mike choking back tears. There is a man in the room too, his arms slouched over his knees, giving Mike &amp; camera a long look.</p>

<p>Be strong Mike for my mom and my sister. Pull yourself together. You can&rsquo;t cry.</p>

<p>Giovana is shut off. Won&rsquo;t talk. Can&rsquo;t blame her. Her dad just passed too. And now her sister&hellip;</p>

<p><em>At the farewell funeral I met Giovana, who looked a lot skinnier and wider-eyed than I had imagined her being. She was only a year older than her sister, and walked shyly around the mourners, talking in side glances with her high school friends who looked pained and out of place. Some of them were smiling &mdash; whether it was the incongruity of it all, or using humor to mask deep sadness, I didn&rsquo;t know.</em></p>

<p>The candlelight vigil was last week, but oh man. It&rsquo;s gonna rain, Mike says, I gotta get there and get the teddy bears in her room.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m feeling out of place. The Kingpin owner comes over to our table. Mike says: you hear the news. They took my daughter. Shot over New Years. The shop owner comes over and clutches Mike&rsquo;s phone loosely. Yeah. He looks concerned, then hands the phone back to Mike.</p>

<p>Everywhere I go I see girls that look like Jabrille. I stop and look at them. The other week we came out here and she bought boots at Skechers here. Right here in Berkeley.</p>

<p>Belinda says now you gotta help me raise the girls. So I say to Giovana: first thing is you can&rsquo;t go outside. Don&rsquo;t hang out with your hoochie mama friends. And she didn&rsquo;t say nothing.</p>

<p>Over our table now Mike slides over to me an open newspaper, the SF Chronicle, opened to an article about Malala, Pakistani girl who got shot by the Taliban. Read this? he asks. So sad.</p>

<p>You gotta be strong, Mike. Wait till this all blows over. I gotta be strong. I gotta be strong for Belinda.</p>

<p><em>Jubrille&rsquo;s viewing was the first viewing I&rsquo;ve ever been at, and she looked&hellip; unnatural. Plastic. There used to be a soul in there. Mike would stand over the casket and kissed her on the forehead. Justin and I stood awkwardly and waited in line and paid our respects and then, feeling a bit of displacement, we sat down in the pews and let Mike sit behind us and rattle on about his plans for the obituary. The entire scene felt unreal. Children running around, crawling under the pews, laughing. Belinda, who I finally met, was nicely put together, chatting it up with loved ones. I&rsquo;d overdressed; I had thought to dress up, but felt self-conscious in my tie and nice shoes. Walking back to the van Justin remarked to me and nobody in particular, is it not crazy that this kind of thing happens in Oakland twice a week?</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A brother like me]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2013/01/09/a-brother-like-me-15/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-09T20:17:46-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2013/01/09/a-brother-like-me-15</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Years have passed since I&rsquo;ve last written about Mike. I see him every once in awhile in Berkeley, still. I think about him from time to time &mdash; wonder how he&rsquo;s doing. I catch him out the corner of my eye the week before I leave for vacation, hanging around at Gypsy&rsquo;s. &ldquo;Mike!&rdquo; I call back to him, and he turns around with a big grin on his face. The sidewalks are soaked.</p>

<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s my birthday tomorrow&rdquo; he tells me, and I remember how close to Christmas it is.</p>

<p>We swap phone numbers. He&rsquo;s in possession of an Android phone now. &ldquo;How does this thing work?&rdquo; he asks and laughs to himself. He&rsquo;s showing me photos of himself, now taking classes at a culinary school in SF. Something about that seems incongruous to me and I chuckle inside&hellip; but Mike, well I believe he has the gumption and work ethic to pull it off. I tell him I owe him a birthday lunch, and we part ways.</p>

<p>&mdash;</p>

<p>Flash forward a couple of weeks, and it&rsquo;s the first Tuesday of the new year. I&rsquo;ve left on a run and Mike&rsquo;s left me a voice mail while on my run. I listen to it on the way back, and his voice is hollow, blue, grief-stricken. &ldquo;Drew,&rdquo; chokes the voice on the other end, &ldquo;<a href="http://www.mercurynews.com/breaking-news/ci_22288885/police-identify-girl-killed-oakland-shooting">they shot my baby girl</a>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Damn.</p>

<p>I look up the news article. Jubrille was 15 years old, wanted to be a teacher, and was on her way to the mall with her sister and another friend. The shooter was another teen.</p>

<p>OAKLAND &mdash; A pile of flowers, candles, teddy bears and farewell notes grew by the hour Monday afternoon on a quiet street in East Oakland, but they were little comfort to Mike Harris.</p>

<p>Harris, whose longtime family friend Jubrille Jordan, 15, was fatally shot at the site Sunday afternoon, was awash in tears as he surveyed the makeshift memorial.</p>

<p>&ldquo;She was my sweetheart. They killed my sweetheart,&rdquo; said Harris, a neatly dressed man in his 50s, as he wiped his eyes. &ldquo;What happened? I don&rsquo;t know, I don't know.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Jubrille was Oakland&rsquo;s 12th child killed in 2012, and its 131st homicide victim in one of the city&rsquo;s deadliest years in recent memory.</p>

<p>&mdash;<a href="http://www.sfgate.com/crime/article/15-year-old-girl-gunned-down-in-Oakland-4158925.php#ixzz2HXjvynid">San Francisco Chronicle, &ldquo;15-year old girl gunned down in Oakland&rdquo;</a></p>

<p>She was also Oakland&rsquo;s final homicide of 2012. Mike picks up, and I barely make out his words through the sobs.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The soul]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2013/01/01/the-soul/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-01T15:29:42-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2013/01/01/the-soul</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Happy new year!</p>

<p>Last night I spent a good amount of time looking back at my journal and saw a few threads that ran through last year:</p>

<p>If 2011 was a year of risk-taking, then 2012, I&rsquo;ve summed up, was a building year, a year to build a rhythm and establish a flow. It was a full year at Blurb, commuting back and forth from SF. Keeping up the same routine at Regen. Stephen Ministry on Mondays, Circuit training Tuesdays, Wednesday mornings with Jeff, home group on Thursdays, Saturday morning runs, Sundays with Betty. Routine and rhythm. It can be good for you.</p>

<p>Knowing who I am, building a flow can be something to settle into but the risk is that I can get too comfortable.  But I found myself up against the reality that your ideals often have a hard time matching up to your reality. So on a serious note, last year was also the first year that I felt like I was just&hellip; <em>coasting</em>. And it felt horrible, the thought and feeling that the kind of life I should have been living should be filled with more risk, more Jesus + his presence. I&rsquo;m learning that I can oftentimes fall into routine and forget myself and why I&rsquo;m here.</p>

<p>There was a season &mdash; I remember it well &mdash; last year when I sat down and wrote down everything I was feeling &mdash; frustration with my life, honest doubts about my purpose and my faith and a slew of questions for God or Jesus or whoever it was that was overseeing my life. Life in Christ is filled with <em>joy</em>, right? Then why wasn&rsquo;t I feeling it? I was tempted to give it all up again.</p>

<p>The intersection of your faith and your daily life can disconnect sometimes, and things had derailed for a long time before I noticed it. The cynicism was subtle, but would crawl into things and inner dialogues. It would rebel against pat answers I saw people giving around me, or the cultural disconnects I&rsquo;d see between the church and Real Life, and a broken world.</p>

<p>The burnout was palpable, but here&rsquo;s the thing: it was something that I didn&rsquo;t do anything about. I kept up the same routines, held the same smiles and had the same answers. But inside there was a gnawing question that reappears from time to time: what is real about my life? Where was that sense that the world is on the brink of something glorious that I felt so often when I was younger&mdash;when things had a surety about them, and answers were more black and white, and joy was real because you were laughing, too? What about the intersection of dirt &amp; the divine, miracles I used to see, or evidence of the supernatural? Where does that stuff just <em>go</em> when you&rsquo;ve lived without them for so long?</p>

<p>Talking to Jeff, I was reminded that the times I felt <em>alive</em> in Christ were the times I was taking risks. So a lot of last year was about asking myself &mdash; where am I going? Where are places I can grow and risks that I can take? And there were a few themes: living in Oakland, identifying with the broken, friendships and brothers, youth &amp; community, silence &amp; solitude.</p>

<p>To be honest, a lot of that has not materialized, and a lot of that were gushy ideas lacking structure and thought and a strong heart.</p>

<p>God, I want that for this year. I want more faith, more experiences of your grace. I want courage to fight for people I love and defend the things I believe in (and vice versa). I want to run toward conflict instead of away from it. I want a stronger, more compassionate heart, and I want to run with people that show that too. But I mainly want to sense your nearness and know you with the familiarity of a son.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advent blue]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/12/24/advent-blue/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-24T23:26:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2012/12/24/advent-blue</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Immanuel, God with us. Immanuel, God with us. Breath. Breath(e). God is with us.</p>

<p>Breathe out, Immanuel. With us. With breath, with us.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
