<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Africa | Finding Momentum]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/category/africa/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-30T21:47:11-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Hao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Re-entry blues]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2009/03/28/re-entry-blues/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-28T20:18:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2009/03/28/re-entry-blues</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The transition back home hasn&rsquo;t been easy. It&rsquo;s been hard to get used to the hustle-and-bustle of life here after coming back from such a pivotal life experience.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t want to forget Africa. I can&rsquo;t. I need to remember, I need to remember the simplicity of living. The endless skies. Friends to chill with when you come home to. Sarah living a couple hundred feet away. Waking up with a vibrant passion and singular purpose.</p>

<p>Here, things are different. If life in Africa was a comfortable stroll, life in the States is doing 90MPH on the freeway. I suppose I&rsquo;m having lane-merge problems.</p>

<p>So it&rsquo;s time to do taxes. And it&rsquo;s time to start work. And don&rsquo;t forget to take care of the yard. Oh, friends aren&rsquo;t as accessible as they once were. And I still haven&rsquo;t put roots down in a church community. And your family&rsquo;s spread out across a couple of continents.</p>

<p>I feel like my mind and my heart are scattered over a million different people and places, and it&rsquo;s frustrating. I need to focus. I need to hear. In many ways, I still haven&rsquo;t felt like I&rsquo;ve come back home&mdash;I&rsquo;m somewhere between departing and arriving.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I’m going to boil this trip down to one word: “surrender”]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2009/03/11/ie28099m-going-to-boil-this-trip-down-to-one-word-e2809csurrendere2809d/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-11T01:23:15-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2009/03/11/ie28099m-going-to-boil-this-trip-down-to-one-word-e2809csurrendere2809d</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/3341037264/"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3312/3341037264_21467a0c9d.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>We meet Douglas, Nelisha, Faith, and friends to share some coffee on our final evening.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/3341037264/"></a></p>

<p>We made it safely back in one piece! Thanks for your continual prayer and support, we couldn&rsquo;t have experienced all this without you. </p>

<h2>One morning, I woke to a revelation that I fear a life wasted.</h2>

<p>I realized that one of my biggest fears was that if I were to totally surrender my life to follow Jesus anywhere, I&rsquo;d become irrelevant. My skills and talents and education and training would be wasted. I wouldn&rsquo;t reach my potential as a Web developer, a designer, an entrepreneur, a musician, or a writer.</p>

<p><em>Would I follow Christ if it meant being:</em></p>

<ul>
<li><p>a laughingstock?</p></li>
<li><p>mocked and despised?</p></li>
<li><p>alone?</p></li>
<li><p>wasted potential?</p></li>
<li><p>poor?</p></li>
</ul>


<p><em>Do I believe that having Christ is worth far more than:</em></p>

<ul>
<li><p>a career?</p></li>
<li><p>familiar friends?</p></li>
<li><p>a relationship?</p></li>
<li><p>a comfortable life?</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Morning after morning, I&rsquo;d stare these questions in the face and wrestle with the voices in my head. Could I really &ldquo;deny [myself], take up [my] cross&rdquo; and follow him? (Mk. 8:34) Even if it meant a life wasted in the world&rsquo;s eyes?</p>

<h2>I was reminded that God is my Treasure, and he is worth far more than anything I can lay claim to.</h2>

<p>No matter how I wrestled with it, I realize that none of my fears held any water in the grand scheme of it all. I couldn&rsquo;t make it work out in such a way where I could justify a life that was surrendered to God with one half and still held onto the other half.</p>

<p>I couldn&rsquo;t deny the richness of the Gospel diamond. I couldn&rsquo;t feel content with a lukewarm existence.</p>

<p>Ultimately, I was reminded that the my greatest desire was to enjoy God, and I couldn&rsquo;t do it unless Jesus really was my Treasure.</p>

<p>About halfway through this trip, I started feeling peace. It was a simple, quiet contentment in living: <em>I have really cool friends here</em> and <em>my skills are useful</em> and the <em>mosquitos have stopped biting, gosh I&rsquo;m almost comfortable</em>. </p>

<p>I&rsquo;m realizing that I was happy not because my conditions for my life were met-that my potential would be realized, or what I had to offer would be utilized-but that I could trust a God who would provide for me, where ultimately he himself was my great reward.</p>

<p>Collin Tomikawa once told us, &ldquo;you don&rsquo;t know how strong the altar is until you put the weight of your entire life on it." </p>

<h2>That&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;ve been learning: that to know the will of God in my life, I must stake my life on the altar and trust.</h2>

<p>Trust-that as I give it all, my good Father lavishes gifts on me: a solid community, fulfillment in using my skills,  and the ultimate gift of Jesus himself. Not to use these benefits as preconditions for surrender, but to hunger for the treasure of Christ so much that these benefits are &ldquo;count[ed] as rubbish&rdquo; in the ultimate calculus of this new life.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve got a lot to learn, and a lot of listening to do as I return home. I don&rsquo;t have concrete answers about the future just yet, but I trust that I&rsquo;ll hear them in the right timing. I&rsquo;ve told God that I&rsquo;m open to wherever he&rsquo;s going to lead me, be it in ministry, in the workforce or in something completely unforeseen and different. I know he&rsquo;s my good Father, my Treasure, and I can follow Him.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mmm, Rusk…]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2009/03/03/mmm-ruske280a6/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-03T21:03:30-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2009/03/03/mmm-ruske280a6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/3291569238/"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3582/3291569238_8ba015b345_m.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/3291569238/">Mmm, Rusk…</a></p>

<p>Originally uploaded by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/people/andrewhao/">andrewhao</a></p>

<p>Allow me to introduce you to the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rusk">rusk</a>. Think of a biscotti, but chunkier. Perfect in coffee or tea for breakfast, lunch, dinner, or midnight snack. Awesome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An afternoon with Zhie]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2009/03/01/an-afternoon-with-zhie/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-01T13:57:01-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2009/03/01/an-afternoon-with-zhie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sure, Jack Bauer sniffs out terrorist sleeper cells to save the world in 24 hours, but did you know…</p>

<p>Zhie heads a womens' empowerment project in Maun.</p>

<p>Zhie harvests maize and peanuts and guavas in her backyard.</p>

<p>Zhie has provided foster care for a local child.</p>

<p>Zhie singlehandedly raises at least three kids at home, at least one of whom is an adopted relative.</p>

<p>Zhie is a community organizer, visiting folks, making connections, informing them of local events.</p>

<p>Zhie is the cool mom all the kids wish they had.</p>

<p>Zhie has the coolest backyard in the neighborhood.</p>

<p>Zhie goes four-wheeling to get to houses out in the remote boroughs.</p>

<p>Zhie does most of the construction in her home by herself.</p>

<p>Zhie knows everybody in Maun (or at least seems to).</p>

<p>Zhie dreams of starting a business of her own.</p>

<p>Zhie is a social worker, getting families the food they need, doing counseling and advising with folks in the community that need it.</p>

<p>Zhie probably needs a vacation.</p>

<p>Needless to say, Zhie&rsquo;s pretty cool. We got to hang out with her all of today after church. First we made some sandwiches for lunch. Then we got to work, fixing up her dresser drawer that was coming out. Sarah and I put together a heroic effort to get everything together before storm clouds began rolling in.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/3320601084/"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3543/3320601084_ecb71ac2ce.jpg?v=0" alt="Here, Mike and me show em what it took to fix up that dresser." /></a></p>

<p>Here, Mike and me show &lsquo;em what it took to fix up that dresser.</p>

<p>Not long after that, we walked over to a local backpackers' camp, where we shared some sodas.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andrewhao/3319787345/"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3621/3319787345_4fe06b796b.jpg?v=0" alt="On the road." /></a></p>

<p>Zhie and Sarah on the road.</p>

<p>Finally, we enjoyed a traditional meal under the clouds and stars. We had a blast laughing, swapping stories, talking politics, and watching lightning electrify the whole sky.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dinner at Nelisha’s (Video)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.andrewhao.com/2009/02/24/dinner-at-nelishae28099s-video/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-24T11:01:25-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.andrewhao.com/2009/02/24/dinner-at-nelishae28099s-video</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nelisha is Sarah&rsquo;s friend from 2006. We bumped into her at church the first week we came in, and we were invited to dinner a week later! Here, as we are waiting for the food to come out, Nelisha is trying to teach Sarah Shona, with limited success.</p>

<p>Check out more of our <a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/haoandrew">Botswana videos</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
